我爱你
I love you, ha-ha
噢耶 钞票快快来 姑娘随我嗨
Cash coming rapidly, chicks coming after me
你拿我的东西做什么 伙计
What'd you do with my stuff, man?
你才是我想找的那个人
You the one I wanna be with ma, actually
我们一拍即合 你是如此特别
I knew you were special
放下你的警惕 你便会沉迷于我
'Cause we hit it off naturally
我会给你全部 而不是一半保留
Had your guards up at first...
你不用着急 姑娘 我们慢慢来
You could take your time gil we gonna move carefully
洗个热水澡吃一顿你准备的大餐
A hot bath water...
当他们问你时 别生气
Now, when it happens, don't act mad.
你必须保持冷静
You gotta look calm.
回答他们的问题
Answer their questions,
但是别多说话
but don't tell 'em nothin' extra.
手不要放在口袋里面
Keep your hands out your pockets.
就算掉了什么东西也别管
You drop somethin', leave that shit where it's at.
麦弗里克
Maverick.
掉了什么东西也别管
Leave that stuff where it's at.
我的错
My bad.
总有一天你们要跟我一起出门
Now, one day, y'all gonna be with me,
我们肯定会被经常拦下来
and you best bet we gonna get pulled over.
不是因为我做了错事
That don't mean I did somethin' wrong.
也许我只是开车不小心违章
Maybe I made a mistake driving
甚至也许我什么都没有做
or maybe I ain't do nothin' at all.
你们会看到我的手这样
You gonna see me with my hands like this.
放在仪表盘上
On the dashboard.
跟我学
Come on.
你们一定记得手不要乱动
Now, you keep your hands posted
因为动作会让警察变得紧张
'cause moving makes the police get all nervous.
如果我不在你们身边 你们就找我
If I ain't with you, you ask for me.
情况会变得非常危险 不要和他们起争执
It can get real dangerous, so don't argue with them...
一定记得把手放在他们能看到的地方
but keep your hands where they can see 'em.
你们就得这么做
This how you gonna act.
清楚了吗
We straight?
我第一次听到爸爸的这番训话时 我九岁
I was nine years old when I first got the talk.
赛文 我同父异母的哥哥 十岁
Seven, my half-brother, was ten.
瑟卡尼只有一岁
Sekani was one.
虽然我们会遇到这样的麻烦
Now, just because we gotta deal with this mess...
但是别忘了做黑人是一种荣耀
don't you ever forget that being black is a honor
因为你们的祖先很伟大
'cause you come from greatness.
这个是黑豹党倡导的
Now, this the Black Panther
十项原则
Ten-Point Program.
这是我们的人权协议
This our own Bill of Rights.
我想让你们学习一下
I want you to learn it.
我会提问你们 测试你们
'Cause Imma ask you about it. Imma quiz you.
至于么 麦弗里克
Really, Maverick?
清楚你们的权利
Know your rights.
清楚你们的价值
Know your worth.
明白吗
You understand?
《你给的仇恨》
忠诚 我的基因里
I got, I got, I got, I got
刻着忠诚
Loyalty, got royalty inside my DNA
斯塔尔 星星多一个r
Starr. Two R's.
我爸爸起的名字
Daddy named me that.
不过别问我多一个r是为了什么
And don't ask me what the extra "R" is for.
我天生如此一直如此
I was born like this, since one like this
天授神胎
Immaculate conception
我变成这样 如此行动
I transform like this, perform like this
是约书亚的武器
Was Yeshua new weapon
我不是思考 我在冥想
I don't contemplate, I meditate
清空你的头脑
Then off your off your head
这会让孩子安睡
This that put-the-kids-to-bed
这我有 那我有 我有 我有 我有
This that I got, I got, I got, I got
其实 我大杀四方 因为这是我的基因
Realness, I just kill shit 'cause it's in my DNA
瑟卡尼 你瞄着点尿啊 小东西
Sekani! Learn how to aim! Dang!
妈妈 瑟卡尼又尿了一地
Mama! Sekani peed everywhere again!
还有小子 把便圈擦干净
And, boy, wipe that seat.
爸妈才17岁的时候就怀了我
Mama and Daddy had me when they were 17.
我姥姥甚至把妈妈赶出了家门
My nana even threw Mama out the house.
她说我爸爸不是好人
Said Daddy was no good...
只是王候帮的一个小卒子
just a pusher for the King Lords gang.
- 嘿 亲爱的 - 你看到我钱包了吗
- Hey, baby. - You seen my wallet?
- 有 我放到梳妆柜上了 - 我找不到了
- Yeah, I put it on the dresser. - I can't find it.
我就放在那了 亲爱的 我记得很清楚
Well, I know it's there, baby. I put it there.
-  早上好 - 早上好
- Good morning. - Good morning.
她发誓说爸爸妈妈要是能成一对
She swore raising the dead was more likely
死人都能复生了
than Mama and Daddy making it.
妈妈
Mama...
他俩于是就在一起 证明姥姥她们错了
They stay proving her and everybody else wrong.
同时也意味着 要确保
And in large part, that means making sure
我们不会走他们的 老路
that we don't make the same mistakes.
我跟你说
You know what?
你为什么不给我老老实实坐那边去
Why don't you just sit your cute butt down
让我专心做点正事 好吗
and let me do what I do. Okay?
哦 是吗
Oh, really?
我也专心做点正事如何
You gonna let me do what I do?
这么大年纪还秀恩爱
Ain't they too old for that?
儿子
Boy...
- 早上好 你们俩 - 早上好
- Good morning, y'all. - Good morning.
他们恩爱秀得有点多余
Their cuteness can be extra,
但依然是可爱的父母
but they're adorable.
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你
我没法不承认
I can't even lie.
他们是我的OTP（One True Pairing：一对情侣）
They're my OTP.
最完美的一对儿
One true pairing.
妈妈和爸爸都生在花园高地
Mama and Daddy were born in Garden Heights.
毕彻大街 万寿菊大道
他们的初吻是在避风港项目的廉租房里
Their first kiss was in the Haven Acres Projects.
酒水商店 T&G税务服务
爸爸曾说我们的生命扎根于此
Daddy says our life is here.
因为我们的同胞生长于此
'Cause our people are here.
这里有鲁本斯先生的烤肉店
We got Mr. Reuben's barbecue...
刘易斯先生的理发店
...Mr. Lewis's barbershop...
32分钟车程外有一间沃尔玛
...a Walmart 32 minutes away...
还有爸爸的店铺
and Daddy's store.
卡特杂货店 啤酒 面包 小吃 牛奶
卡特杂货店 就是你平时买牛奶
Carter's Grocery is where you get your milk,
新港短烟 辣薯饼
Newport shorts, Hot Cheetos,
听到最新的八卦
hot gossip,
来杯饮料 可口可乐 镇上最冰爽的啤酒
还有买到其他你急用的东西的地方
and anything else that you might need in a hurry.
妈妈认为爸爸害怕改变
Mama thinks Daddy is scared of change.
她从小就离开了花园
She left the Garden when she was a little girl.
她也想我们离开这里
And she wants us to get out too.
不论如何 你都得时刻做好准备
Either way, you gotta stay ready.
因为花园高地时刻会给你考验
'Cause Garden Heights is always gonna be ready for you.
赛文 你今晚要住你妈妈家里
Seven? Now, are you staying at your mama's house
还是回家
or with us tonight?
在我妈妈那里 直到国王回来为止
At Mama's. As long as King ain't there.
那就是国王
And then there's King.
他是王侯帮的头
He runs the King Lords.
我爸爸从前是他的心腹
My dad used to be his right-hand man.
你在高中
The high school is where you go...
可能会挨揍 吸毒 怀孕 甚至被人杀死
...to get jumped, high, pregnant, or killed.
我们不去那个学校
We don't go there.
自从我朋友娜塔莎出事以后
Not since what happened to my friend Natasha.
于是妈妈送我们到另一所学校
So Mama sent us to another school
那里都是立志考大学的孩子
where everyone's college-bound.
瑟卡尼
- Sekani? - Yeah?
亲爱的 再回答一次你名字的含义
Baby, remind me what your name means again.
快乐
Joy!
没错 意思是
Yes! So that means I want you
我想让你能快快乐乐
to be just as big a joy at school
在学校和在家一样快乐 好吗
as you are at home, okay?
好
Okay!
别那么大声
But less loud!
为什么要喊啊
Why you yelling?
威廉姆森学校
祝你们一天顺利
You guys have a good day.
- 爱你 妈妈 - 我也爱你 瑟卡尼
- Love you, Mommy! - I love you too, Sekani.
花园高地是一回事
Garden Heights is one world.
威廉姆森则是另一个世界
Williamson is another.
我必须要分清楚
And I gotta keep it separate.
所以来到这里 我就变成了斯塔尔二号
So when I'm here, I'm Starr Version Two.
美洲虎主场
- 晚点见 哥哥 - 回见
- See you later, bro. - Peace out.
这就意味着在我脑中按下一个开关
That means flipping a switch in my brain.
威廉姆森的斯塔尔不用俚语讲话
Williamson Starr doesn't use slang.
说唱里用的词 她就不用
If a rapper would say it, she doesn't.
哪怕是她的白人朋友用 她也不用
Even if her white friends do.
嘿 亲爱的
Hey, boo.
- 嘿 你好吗 - 我很好 妹子
- Hey, how are you? - I'm good, girl.
俚语会显得他们酷 会显得我痞
Slang makes them cool. Slang makes me "hood."
哟 鞋子很赞啊
Yo! Those kicks are lit!
谢了 这是乔十一
Thanks. Space Jams.
威廉姆森版斯塔尔平易近人
Williamson Starr is approachable.
不甩眼色 不大吼大叫
No stank eyes or yelling because
因为威廉姆森版斯塔尔不愿起争执
Williamson Starr is non-confrontational.
简单地说 威廉姆森版斯塔尔不给人任何理由
Basically, Williamson Starr doesn't give anyone a reason
叫她贫民区来的孩子
to call her ghetto.
而我讨厌自己这样做
And I hate myself for doing it.
让我对付他 我要狠狠教训他
Let me at him. I'll kick his ass.
海莉 你太暴力了
Hailey, you're violent.
噢 好吧 要是有人
Uh, okay. If someone tries to do
敢对我的朋友不好 我必须挺身而出
some shit to my girl, I have to get him.
我说真的 斯塔尔 我会去找他
I'm serious, Starr. I will go after him.
教训他的
I will kick his ass.
我根本不在乎的 你告诉我一声就好
I do not care. You just say the word.
海莉昨晚一定看了
Hailey must've watched Straight Outta Compton
《冲出康普顿》
again last night.
你说一声 我就会动手的
You just say the word, and I'm gonna do it.
你对他说什么了
What did you say to him?
我俩现在不怎么讲话了 所以
We're not really talking right now, so...
是谁不愿意和对方讲话
Who's not really talking to whom?
克里斯骗斯塔尔去他家
Well, Chris lured Starr over to his house
然后突然掏出避孕套给她看
and sprung a condom on her.
你怎么跟他说的
What did you say?
不 不 不 你们做什么了
No, no, no. What did you do?
避孕套什么尺寸的
What size was it?
玛雅 我的天呐
Maya! Oh, my God!
我只告诉你你需要知道的信息
You're on a "need to know."
好吧 可是我需要知道啊
Okay! And I need to know.
听着 克里斯很好 我只是没有准备好
Look, Chris is great, but I'm just not ready.
我总有一天会准备好的 不过他想当然
And eventually, I'll get there, but he just assumed.
想当然 这是死罪了
Assuming. Punishable by death.
那你打算像泰勒·斯威夫特一样处理么
So, you're gonna Taylor Swift this?
你看她
She doesn't even rank
一点都不生气
on the angry girlfriend scale anymore.
不 我要像碧昂丝一样处理他
Nah. I'm gonna Beyonce his ass.
看着
Watch.
我其实想和索朗格一样在电梯里揍他一顿
I really wanna "Elevator Solange" his ass.
我盯着你看了好久好久
I've been watching you for some time
眼光挪不开你如海洋般的眼眸
Can't stop staring at those ocean eyes
燃烧的城市 满是炸弹的天空
Burning cities and napalm skies
见鬼 他和我一样
Damn. He's wearing
都穿乔十一
the same Space Jam Elevens as mine.
他知道我对乔丹鞋没有抵抗力
He knows Jordans are my weakness.
他身上是老帆船沐浴露的味道
He smells like Old Spice.
他的嘴唇很软
His lips are soft.
不公平
No fair
你知道如何让我哭泣
You really know how to make me cry
当你用那海洋般的眼睛看着我
When you gimme those ocean eyes...
他假装自己是DJ卡利德
He swear he's DJ Khaled.
我承认 每次都会打动我
I can't lie. It still gets me every time.
别这样 不要
Nuh-uh. Nope.
我不喜欢你那天做的事情
I don't like what you did the other day.
斯塔尔 我很抱歉
Starr, I'm sorry.
是我错了 我混蛋
- I messed up. Bad. - Mm-hmm.
但是我觉得我们关系越来越好
But I keep thinking that we're getting closer...
我想周六约你出去
and ask to take you out on Saturday,
你没答应我
and you don't say yes.
-我很忙 - 是啊
- I'm busy. - Right.
每次都忙
Every time?
于是我就想也许你希望我先见家长
So I figure maybe you want me to meet your parents first.
可每次我想去你家 你都不同意
But whenever I ask to come over, you never say yes.
他们也忙
They're busy too.
好像大家都很忙啊 斯塔尔
Well, it seems like everyone's busy, Starr.
那我就想了 我怎么样才能和我女朋友更进一步呢
So then I think, "How do I get closer to my own girlfriend?
是不是她想要跳过
Maybe she wants to skip the whole flowers
送花送巧克力的阶段 直奔主题
and chocolate part and just get right to it."
克里斯 你这样未兔太蠢了
Chris, you are acting a damn fool,
如果你认为我和那些饥渴的小女孩一样
if you think I'm one of these little thirsty girls
花枝招展引人上钩
running around here that you can hit.
斯塔尔 你肯定不是
Starr, you're not.
你对我来说非常重要 好吗
You're way more important than that to me, okay.
我们已经交往将近六个月了
We've been dating for almost six months.
如果你还看不明白着点
And if you can't tell that by now,
那我也不知道你想我让说什么了
then I don't know what else you want me to say.
除了我想你
Other than I miss you.
一直想你
A lot.
这曲子是我为你写的
I made that beat for you.
来嘛 你得承认我写得很赞
Come on. You gotta tell me that's fire.
还行吧
It's a'ight.
我要听你说实话
I wanna hear you say it.
还不错
It's okay.
哇 好吧
Wow. Okay.
那我只能想办法测试一下了
I guess that means I gotta test it.
我很清楚
I'm fully aware
有人会责怪他
that some people would accuse him
模仿黑人
of acting black,
不过克里斯就是这样子
but this is just Chris.
而且他能把我逗笑
And he makes me laugh.
嘿 跳得不错 哥们
Hey! Get it, man!
我的天
Oh, my God.
别转圈了 过来
Don't spin. Come on.
你现在能原谅我了吗
Do you forgive me now?
嗯
Yeah.
会有人好奇
We get the questions.
他为什么会和她在一起
Why is he dating her?
老实说 我有时候也会想这个问题
On the real, I sometimes wonder the same thing.
盯着我看的通常都是有钱的白人女孩
Now, the stares usually come from the rich white girls.
但是她们远没有胆量
But they're way too scared to actually
当面对我们说什么
say anything to our faces.
让我周六带你出去吧
Let me take you somewhere on Saturday.
去做什么
To do what?
去吃汉堡
We can eat burgers.
桌上足球我可以让你赢
I let you beat me in foosball...
让我赢
Let me beat you?
然后可以
- Mm-hmm. - And then we can kiss
在摩天轮上接吻
on a Ferris wheel.
你太俗套了
That is so cheesy.
我就这么点追求
That's what I got.
好吧 不过我们可以改周日去吗
Okay. But can we do Sunday instead?
我去接你
I'll pick you up?
我来找你
I'll meet you.
奥古斯丁家见
Augustine's?
恩 三点见
Mm-hmm. Three o'clock?
太浪漫了
So romantic.
你真傻
You are a fool.
我是你的傻子
I'm your fool.
是啊
Yeah.
确实如此
That is true.
克里斯是身为斯塔尔二号最好的一面
Chris is the best thing about being Starr Version Two.
有时候我只想和他这样下去
And sometimes I think that's all I want to be.
我不信任你 因为你用左手行礼
I don't trust you 'cause you dap with the left hand
直到周末来临
Until the weekend comes around.
我把右手放在我的腰部
That's my right hand
我的狗先到 全都磕了药
All my dogs come first all lost in the purp
我也不觉得自己属于这个聚会
I'm not sure I belong at this party either though.
不论是哪个版本的我
Neither version of me.
左手 右手
Left hand, right hand
右手 右手
Right hand, right hand
左手右手一起摇摆
Left be working then the right
出去又回来
Coming right back
纠正错误的存在
Yeah I left to get it right
现在我已经回来
Now I'm right back
嘿
Hey!
我向粉丝展示我的爱与感激
I show love and affection to all my fans...
肯雅大概是
Kenya's about the only person
我在花园高地唯一的朋友
I hang out with in Garden Heights.
不过我发誓她有时候能把我气死
Even if she gets on my nerves sometimes. I swear.
姐们
Man.
怎么了
What?
你说
I mean,
来这里的所有姑娘都精心打扮
every girl in here all laid and slayed
可你偏偏穿得普普通通
but you wanna come up in here looking basic as hell.
啥 姐姐 这可是复古乔三代
What? Girl, these are the Retro Threes.
经典 舒适 而且等着瞧吧
Classic and comfortable, and watch.
当你今晚结束之后像个跛脚羚羊一样的时候
You're gonna be wishing that you was wearing them tonight
你会巴不得自己穿的是这双鞋哈
when you limpin' out of here like a broke-down gazelle. Bam.
喂 你穿的不是我哥的帽衫吗
Man, ain't that my brother hoodie?
我们老哥的帽衫 是啊 没错 肯雅
Our brother's hoodie, Kenya, yeah.
你再这么打扮 他们肯定会觉得
Yeah, dressed like that, got folks thinking
你是我女朋友了
you're my girlfriend.
肯雅 如果我知道
Kenya, if I had known
你要带我来这个地方
following you to this party meant that I would be
意味着我要化超浓的版本的妆
on some Extreme Makeover Starr Edition mess,
我就待在家里
I would've stayed home
看我的《新鲜王子》重播了
and watched my Fresh Prince reruns.
妹子 你真应该把90年代那一套抛弃了
Oh, girl, you got to let the 90s perish.
你要怎么办
What now?
那个贱人德尼西亚
There go that trick, Denasia.
我真是看不惯她
Ooh, I can't stand her ass.
不停地说
Always talking smack about how I'm trying
我想要抢她家的丑男人
to steal her ugly-ass man.
哦 真的吗
Oh, for real?
姐们 你能去上那所私人学校太幸运了
Man, you so lucky you go to that private school.
你不用跟那种贱人打交道
You don't gotta deal with hoes like that.
不 我学校一样有贱人
No. There's hoes at my school, too.
相信我 贱人遍布全球
Trust me, hoedom is universal.
贱人 看我瞪死你 看我瞪死你
Feel my stink eye, bitch. Feel my stink eye.
我们今晚一定要她好看
Oh, we about to handle her tonight.
慢着 我们
Hold up. We?
咋啦 你现在高贵到不给我撑腰了
What? What, you too good now to have my back?
- 你别跟我 - 别跟我怎么啊
- Don't even! - Don't even what?
你带我来就是要我帮忙对付那个贱人吗
You only brought me here to tag team a bitch?
你又没别的事情做
Ain't like you had shit else to do.
我这是帮你解闷
I'm doing your black ass a favor.
哇 我的天 我有朋友的好吗
Oh, my God! You do know I have friends, right?
那些你学校的中产女孩不算啊
Them bougie girls from your school do not count.
哟 肯雅
Yo, Kenya!
你好吗
What up?
- 嘿 - 你好吗
- Hey. - How you doing?
- 我很好 - 嘿 姐们
- I'm good. - Hey, boo.
你可不能让你妹妹
Now, you know you ain't have to bring
打扮成这样过来啊
your sister out dressed like that.
我们不是姐妹
We ain't sisters.
是啊 我妈
Yeah, just 'cause my mama
和他爸生了赛文
and her daddy made Seven,
不代表我们是亲戚
don't make us related.
虽然她是我的好姐妹
I mean, she my girl,
但是 我们并不是亲人
but Seven don't make us kin.
总之 别管斯塔尔了 碧昂卡
Anyway, leave Starr alone, Bianca.
人家习惯和白人一起玩
She's used to partying amongst the whites.
我猜他们喜欢吃摇头丸
Yo, I bet they be poppin' Mollies
和各种药片 对吧
and all kind of pills, don't they?
然后听泰勒·斯威夫特的歌还跟着唱
Listening to Taylor Swift ass trying to sing.
你们这也太离谱 好吧 其实是真的
Y'all are just reaching... Wait, that's true.
是吧 对吧 我们都清楚
- Exactly. We know. - Yeah.
我刚刚在讨论怎么教训一下德尼西亚
Anyway, I was talking about rollin' up on Denasia ass.
- 又是那个贱人 - 是啊
- Old trick. - Yep.
你知道她背地里
You know she be running
说你坏话了吧
her mouth about you, right?
- 知道 - 那贱人就欠收拾
- Word. - Bitch need her ass beat.
我们走 来吧
- Well, let's go. - Come on.
- 你来吗 - 不了
- You comin'? - No.
那我也不能一晚上都看着你
Well, I'm not babysitting you all night,
你自己小心吧
so, like, take care of yourself.
吓人
Scary.
晚上7点半 耶
7:30, you lying
每次我都起鸡皮疙瘩 耶
I get those goosebumps every time, yeah
你的到来 耶
You come around, yeah
你让我放松
You ease my mind
你让我觉得一切都好
You make everything feel fine
担心那些风言风语
Worry about those condoms
卡里尔
Khalil.
你被那些人围着
Look at the sea of people parting for you
就好像黑皮肤的摩西
like you a brown-skinned Moses.
每次我都起鸡皮疙瘩
I get those goosebumps every time
你的酒窝
Those dimples.
我该怎么面对它们
What am I supposed to do with that?
我曾经跟你一起
And I used to take baths with you
在你奶奶的澡盆里洗澡
in your grandmama's tub when she used
她以前照顾我和赛文的时候
to babysit me and Seven.
卡里尔 那双棕色的眼睛
Weird what the sight of Khalil's brown eyes
用奇怪的目光看着我
do to me now.
斯塔尔
Starr!
我去
Damn.
你居然
What?
有段日子没见到你了
It's been a minute.
你怎么样 都在忙什么
What's up? Where you been at?
上学 打篮球 各种事情
School. Basketball. Keeps me busy.
但是我一直都在我爸爸店里
But I'm always up at Daddy's store.
你才是消失的那个
You the one no one sees anymore.
的确 我最近确实也在忙
Yeah, I've been a little busy myself.
怎么啦 干什么
What's up? What?
没事啊
Nothin.
你奶奶和卡梅隆还好吗
How's your grandmama and Cameron doing?
他刚过十岁 对吧
He just turned ten, right?
是啊 他们很好
Yeah. They all right.
不过奶奶病了
Grandma's sick though.
医生说她得了癌症还是什么的
The doctor say she got cancer or some shit.
该死 我很难过
Damn. I'm sorry, okay.
没事 她在接受化疗
Yeah, she's taking chemo.
但是她最担心的事情是
But really the only thing she's worried about
要在头上戴假发
is putting the wig on top of her head.
我在想要不要把她的抢过来 快看
Shit, I'm thinking about taking hers. Look.
- 她跳的真嗨 - 她太投入了 太投入了
- She turnt up. - She's going in.
来吧 让我见识一下你也像她一样投入
Come on, let me see you turn up like she turn up.
耶 耶
Yeah. Yeah.
你知道这首歌
You know this.
我没想到你喜欢这种
See, I would've thought you was into
独立摇滚或者偏乡村民谣
the indie rock or maybe country or...
每个人都知道这首歌
Everyone knows this song.
我是说 你平时不都和那群白人孩子一起玩吗
I mean, I know you be hanging with all the white kids.
- 我就随便问问 - 闭嘴 你快别闹
- I'm just saying. - Shut up. You better stop.
见鬼 我踩到你鞋子了吗 对不起
Oh, damn! Did I scuff you? I'm so sorry.
不 不 不 住手 别蹭
No, no, no. Stop. Stop. Don't scrub.
一定要轻轻擦
Gotta be gentle.
你每次用错误的方法擦鞋
Every time a sneaker is cleaned improperly,
都会害死一只小猫咪
a kitten dies.
你这个球鞋狂
Sneakerhead!
好了 我看出来了
Okay, well, I see you.
你穿着这身说明没少赚钱呢
You obviously making big money if you rockin' those.
怎么搞的 哥们 啥情况
What up, bro? What's up, man?
你想咋地 哥们 这是我的地盘
You know what is, bro. This is my area.
谁允许你来这里的啊
Ain't no business doing over here, bro?
别闹了
Cut it out!
你动我啊 伙计 怎么搞的 哥们
Move, man! What's up, man?
来啊
Come on.
总会出这种事 你瞧见没有
It's always some shit. You see that?
我们开个聚会
We can't even have a party
都会有人吃枪子
without somebody getting shot at.
真见鬼
Damn.
只有上帝能审判我 是吗
Only God can judge me, that right?
只有上帝能审判我 别人不行
Only God baby, nobody else, nobody else
你们其他人少惹我 说真的
All you other motherfuckers get out my business, really
也许是我视而不见
Perhaps I was blind to the facts
背后捅刀
Stabbed in the back
图派克《只有上帝能审判我》
我连兄弟也不能相信
I couldn't trust my own homies
不过是一群鼠辈
Just a bunch of dirty rats
吞云吐雾神志不清
Will I succeed paranoid from the weed...
哥们 你自己就听这种老歌
Man, so you gonna come at me for my music
还有脸说我的音乐品味差
while you listening to this old stuff?
老歌
Oh, old stuff?
我可要赶你下车了
You better get up out my car with that.
图派克可是真理
Tupac is the truth.
可不 20年前的
Yeah, 20 years ago.
不 哪怕是现在
No, even still, right now.
听我说
Listen, let me tell you something.
派克曾经说 暴徒生活意思是
Pac said, THUG LIFE means
你给婴儿灌输的暴力会毁了所有人
"The Hate U Give Little Infants Fucks Everybody."
懂了吧
T-H-U-G-L-I-F-E.
意思是什么
Meaning what?
意思是这个社会在我们小时候
Meaning what society gives to us when we little
教给我们的东西
comes back to bite them in the ass
当我们长大成人后会狠狠报复他们
when we grow up, and we wild out.
你能理解吗
You get that?
当然理解
Damn. Yeah.
派克的歌永远不会过时
Pac's gonna always be relevant.
你到底要不要告诉我你最近在忙什么 卡里尔
So you gonna tell me why you really been busy, Khalil?
因为我那份工作给的钱太少了
Because that McJob that I had didn't make nothin' happen.
再加上医院知道奶奶得病之后
And plus grandma got fired from the hospital
就把她开除了
when they found out she was sick.
这太惨了 卡里尔 真的
Damn, that's messed up, K, for real.
你懂的 我们需要生活
You know, we got needs.
如果你是去贩毒了
If you selling that stuff...
嘿 别这样
Hey, come on now.
管好你自己就行了 斯塔尔
Mind your business, Starr-Starr.
别担心我的事情
Don't worry about me.
我这也是迫不得已
I'm doing what I gotta do.
你有时候真是要气死我
Man, you piss me off sometimes.
是吗 你现在生气了吗
Oh, yeah? So you pissed off right now?
是啊
Yeah.
你看着可不怎么生气
You don't really look too pissed off.
我订看不出来你到底生不生气
So, you know, I couldn't tell if you was pissed off.
我真的很生气
I'm really mad at you.
我穿过墓地 和泥土讲话
...talking to the dirt
我宁愿有骨气地死 也不愿苟活
I'd rather die like a man than live like a coward
天国有属于我们的乐园
There's a ghetto up in Heaven
我们大喊黑人万岁
And it's ours, Black Power
我们做着
Is what we scream as we dream
偏执的梦
In a paranoid state
我们的命运就是备受仇恨
And our fate is a lifetime of hate
我收到肯雅信息了 她没事
Oh, I just heard from Kenya. She's good.
那就好
Cool.
那个 我们为什么停车
So, why are we stopped?
因为我想和你说话时候
Because I wanna look at you in your eyes
能看着你的眼睛
when I'm talking to you.
这样不对吗
- Somethin' wrong with that? - Hmm.
这个道理没错
Not inherently, no.
道理没错
Not inherently.
- 道理没错 - 怎么了
- Not inherently. - What?
你那个学校把你教坏了
That school got you messed up.
我有一次还看到你了
I saw you out there one time, too.
什么时候
When?
你们去的路上 你穿着裙子
Y'all was headed there. You had your little skirt on.
长袜 还背着书包
Your knee-highs. Your backpack.
一副整齐的样子
You was ready.
什么叫你看到我了
What do you mean you saw me one time?
你难道在跟踪我吗
So you stalking me now?
是啊
Whoa, now.
才怪
No.
我就是正巧看到了 仅此而已
I just like seeing you. That's all.
我们小时候基本
We used to see each other damn near every day
- 每天都会见到 - 是啊
- when we was kids. - Yeah.
你还记得我们以前玩哈利·波特的游戏吗
Do you remember when we used to play Harry Potter?
记得
Yeah.
我们给自己起什么名字来着
What did we call ourselves? Uh...
- 邻家三人组 - 邻家三人组
- The Hood Trio. - The Hood Trio.
一群不好惹的十岁巫师
We were some badass 10-year-old wizards.
惹不起
Bad.
你还留着你的魔杖吗
You still have your wand?
当然没 早就不见了
Hell, no. I ain't got that wand.
我的魔杖不见了
I don't have the wand.
我知道你肯定留着呢
I know you still have it.
没有 我把魔杖扔了
I don't have it. I threw it away
因为你不让我当哈利
because you would never let me be Harry.
- 因为你是罗恩啊 - 但我其实更像哈利
- Because you were Ron! - But I was really Harry.
不 我才是哈利
No. I was Harry.
你是罗恩 娜塔莎是赫敏
You were Ron. Natasha was Hermione.
好吧
Okay.
还记得我们第一次接吻吗
So that first kiss we had?
在教堂地下室的时候
In the church basement. Mm-hmm.
是啊
Yep.
我们真是不虔诚
Man, we were some heathens.
你意思是我亲的是哈利·波特
So you telling me that I was kissing Harry Potter?
对啊
Yeah.
你亲的 是他
Yeah, you were.
好吧
All right.
那我现在亲的是谁
So who am I kissing right now?
卡里尔 我
Khalil, I...
我有男朋友了
I got a boyfriend.
是啊 我听说了
Yeah, I heard.
我不想知道的
I didn't wanna hear.
但是没关系
But it's all good.
真的吗
Really?
我们认识一辈子了 斯塔尔
We've been together our whole lives, Starr.
有的是时间
We got time.
好吗
All right?
都看着我
All eyes on me
我猜你晕了
I bet you got it twisted
不知道该信谁了
You don't know who to trust
很多人都想像我们一样唱歌
So many playa hatin'...
见鬼 该怎么办
Damn. What I do?
我不知道
I don't know.
8C 14街与3街路口
Eight-Charlie, Fourteenth and Third.
见鬼
Damn.
卡里尔 把你的手放到仪表盘上面
Khalil, put your hands on the dash
让他看到
where he can see them.
卡里尔 把你的手放到仪表盘上面 我不逗你
Khalil, put your hands on the dash! I'm not playing.
斯塔尔 我们什么也没做也就又往前开了15米吧
Starr, we ain't done nothing. What'd we drive, like 50 feet?
快点
Please.
求你了 听我的吧
Please. Just do it.
好吧
Okay.
先生 能帮我把车窗摇下来吗
Sir, can you roll your window down for me?
开始了
Here we go.
我需要看一下你的驾照
I need to see your driver's license and registration.
为什么 我做了什么
For what? What'd I do?
先生 请出示驾照
Sir, license and registration.
卡里尔 把你的手放到仪表盘
Khalil, keep your hands on the dash.
斯塔尔 我的手要是一直放在上面不动
Starr, how am I supposed to get him my license
还怎么给他驾照
and registration if I have to stay still?
我就想知道你为什么拦我的车
I wanna know why you pulling me over.
你刚才没有打转向灯
You failed to signal a lane change.
把音乐关掉
- Come on. - Turn the music off.
为什么 我能听到你讲话啊
Why? I can hear you.
- 拜托 卡里尔 - 关掉
- Please, Khalil! - Turn it off.
这是我的车 你怎么能告诉我...
This is my car. So how can you tell me...
请下车
Step out of the car.
你没有权利要求我这么做
You ain't got no right to do this to me.
听着 我依照法律命令你
Listen, I'm giving you a lawful order.
卡里尔 按他说的做
Khalil, listen to him.
是因为我没有打转向灯
Is it for failing to signal my lane change
还是因为我没关音乐 到底哪个
or for failing to turn down my music? Which one?
先生 请下车 快点
Sir, out of the car, now!
弗里蒙特警局 115号
要么你自己下车
Either you get out of the car yourself,
要么我把你请下来
or I'm gonna do it for you.
快
Now!
把手机放下
Drop the phone!
你干嘛不直接给我开罚单
Yo, why don't you just give me my ticket?
手放在车上 你身上有东西吗
Hands on the car. Anything on you?
不 我身上什么也没有
No, there's nothing on me.
- 毒品呢 - 没有 哥们
- Any drugs? - Nah, man.
能把驾照拿出来吗
Can you remove your driver's license, please?
- 你从哪儿找到她的 - 我认识她
- Where'd you find her? - I know her.
她是我朋友
That's my friend.
你今晚是要买毒品吗
You looking for a score tonight?
啥 买毒品 嘿 你在说什么呢
What? A score? Yo, come on, man.
把手放在车上 别乱动
Keep your hands on the car. Do not move.
帮我查一个驾照
Can I get a license run on...
见鬼
Shit.
我的手机呢
Where's my phone?
见鬼
Shit!
斯塔尔 你没事吧
Starr, you okay?
- 你没事吧 - 回去站着啊
- You all right? - Go back where he told you.
他得花点时间搞警察那一套
He gonna take his time doing whatever he gotta do.
我不说笑 快回去
I'm not playing. Go back.
好了 好了 你在翻我的车做什么
Yo, but come on! Why you messing up my car?
- 按他说的做 卡里尔 - 好 好的 冷静
- Just listen to him, Khalil! - Okay! All right, chill.
别动 停下
Stop right there! Stop!
不要动
- Do not move. - No. No.
不 不 不
No.
不 卡里尔
No, Khalil.
安静 女士
Be quiet, ma'am.
你坐下
You sit down.
不
No.
警官求助 已开火
Officer needs help. Shots fired.
击倒一名嫌疑人 另一名已缉拿
One suspect down. The other in custody.
请求救护车
Requesting an ambulance.
你干了什么
What did you do?
安静 女士
Be quiet, ma'am.
快救救他
Help him!
待着别动 不要动 行么
I want you to stay where you are! Do not move, okay?
他在流血 快救救他 快点
He's bleeding! Help him! Come on!
他在流血
He's bleeding!
在哪呢 武器在哪呢
Where is it? Where's the weapon?
啊 枪呢 枪在哪里
Okay? The gun! Where is it?
什么枪
What gun?
在哪
Where...
该死
Shit!
- 卡里尔 - 见鬼 见鬼
- Khalil! - Shit! Shit!
卡里尔 看着我 求你 看着我 卡里尔
Khalil, look at me! Come on, look at me, Khalil.
求求你 看着我 看着我 求你了
Come on, look at me! Look at me, come on!
卡里尔 看着我
Khalil, come on, look at me!
我就在这儿 你没事的 好吗
I'm right here. You're okay, all right?
救护车马上就来了 你能听到吗
There's a ambulance coming. Can you hear it?
就来了 会把你治好的
It's coming. It's gonna take care of you.
你没事的 好吗
You're gonna be fine, all right?
你一定会没事的 别害怕
You're gonna be okay. Don't be scared.
求你了 看着我
Come on, look at me!
看着我 卡里尔 求你
Look at me, Khalil. Come on!
深呼吸 斯塔尔
Breathe, Starr.
斯塔尔 深呼吸
Starr, breathe.
哪个警察干的
Who did that, man?
那个警察...
The officer who did it...
我理解 我知道
I understand that. I know.
我是戈麦斯警探
I'm Detective Gomez.
这是我的搭档 威尔克斯紧探
And this is my partner, Detective Wilkes.
丽莎·卡特 我是她妈妈
Uh, Lisa Carter. I'm her mother.
斯塔尔·卡特
Starr Carter.
你能告诉我们今晚发生的事情吗
Can you tell us what happened tonight, Starr?
我去了一个聚会
I went to this party.
卡里尔也在那里
And Khalil was there, too.
卡里尔为什么去那里
Why was Khalil there?
和其他人一样吧 我猜
Same as everybody else, I guess.
就是去玩的
Just recreational purposes.
聚会上的目击者称那里发生了
Witnesses at the party stated that there was
争吵和枪击
an altercation and gunshots.
卡里尔和那件事有关吗
Did Khalil have anything to do with it?
没
Nah.
我是说 没有
I mean... no.
我们只是在聊天
We were, uh, just talking...
他们打起来的时候
when the fight broke out.
他提议送我回家
He offered to take me home
因为他想确保我能安全到家
because he wanted to make sure that I got home safely.
然后115号警察就无故拦下了我们
And that's when 115 pulled us over for no reason.
谁
Who?
那个警察
The officer.
那是他的警徽编号
That's his badge number.
我记得
I remember it.
斯塔尔 你知道卡里尔为什么探身进车里吗
Starr, do you know why Khalil reached into the car?
我觉得他是想看看我是否安全
I think he was checking to see that I was okay.
你觉得
You think?
你不知道
You don't know?
不 我不知道
No, I don't know.
因为
Because?
因为事情就是这样子
Because that's when it happened.
你和卡里尔
- Did you and Khalil... - Uh...
你能让她缓缓吗
Would you please just give her a second?
那等你准备好 好吗 宝贝
Whenever you're ready. Okay, baby?
我们理解这对你来说很艰难
We understand that this is hard right now.
真的理解吗
Do you?
是的 卡特夫人 我们理解
Yes, Mrs. Carter, we do.
慢慢来
Take your time.
你们聚会时候饮酒了吗
Did you drink alcohol at the party?
不 我不喝酒
No, I don't drink.
卡里尔呢
Did Khalil?
我没看到他喝
Not that I saw.
你有没有见过卡里尔贩毒
Did you ever see Khalil sell narcotics?
不 我从未亲眼见过卡里尔贩毒或吸毒
No, I never personally saw Khalil sell drugs or do drugs.
但你知道他有做过
But you knew that he did?
你连一个关于那名警察的问题
You have not asked my daughter
都没有问过我女儿
one question about the cop.
我们想了解事件的全貌 夫人 仅此而已
We just want the whole picture, miss. That's all.
那你倒是问当时的情况啊
Well, you ask questions about what happened.
115号杀了卡里尔
115 killed Khalil.
卡里尔什么也没有做
And he didn't do anything wrong.
所以我就不懂
So I don't know what more
你们还想要什么样的全貌
of a bigger picture you need!
没她的事了
She's done here.
走吧 丽莎 没事的 斯塔尔
Come on, Lisa. Come on, Starr.
你认识她
You know her?
当然 她是我侄女
Yeah, she's my niece.
没事 没事
All right. All right.
我在这呢
I'm here.
没事
Yeah.
吐出来吧 吐出来吧
Let it out. Let it out.
放松 吐出来吧 对 吐出来
Easy. Let it out. Yeah, let it out.
没事 没事
Here. Here.
没事的 宝贝 没事的 没事了
It's okay, baby. It's okay, baby. It's okay.
没事了
It's okay.
给 喝点水
Here. Drink this now.
没事了 宝贝
It's okay, baby.
噩梦总是最惨痛的记忆
Nightmares are always the worst right after.
瑟卡尼 别
Sekani, no.
给斯塔尔 让她先吃
Starr first. Let her eat.
要知道 不是每个人都和你一样有超能力
You know, not everybody got superpowers like you.
绽放你的光芒吧
Shine your light.
我给你起这个名字是有原因的
I ain't name you Starr by accident.
瑟卡尼
Sekani!
别闹
No!
谢谢
Thank you.
你是那孩子唯一真正的朋友
You the only real friend that boy ever had.
他对我也是一样 罗萨莉夫人
He was mine, too, Miss Rosalie.
警察来过
Police came by.
你当时和他在一起吗 斯塔尔
Was you with him, Starr?
是的 夫人
Yes, ma'am.
谢天谢地 他走的时候不是孤身一人
Thank God he didn't leave this world alone.
你从小就陪伴他长大
You been by his side from day one,
一直陪他到最后
and you stayed all the way to the end.
他在卖那东西 你知道吗
He was selling that stuff, you know.
除了王侯帮之外不会有别的人
Can't be for nobody but King.
你真有胆子来啊
You got some nerve coming in here.
他来这里做什么
What's he doing here?
嘿 卡洛斯
Hey, Carlos.
你好 丽莎
Hi, Lisa.
借过
Excuse me.
罗萨莉夫人 我来是为了
Miss Rosalie, I came by to tell you
向您表示哀悼
I'm sorry for your loss.
潘姆和我都在为您祈祷
And Pam and I have been praying for you.
克里斯 你来吗
非常感谢
Thank you so much.
如果有什么需要我帮忙的
There's anything I can do for you...
请一定记得跟我说
know we are here for you.
爱您
Love you.
奥古斯丁
斯塔尔 你今天要去哪儿 晚点去玛雅家
好的宝贝 没问题 你来吗
我的天 我很抱歉 我来不了了
克里斯 不是吧 又来
小心
Look out.
我很想你
那怎么处理的
So what's the deal?
把他关起来了吗
His ass in jail?
他们会让他停职留薪
They're gonna place him on paid administrative leave.
这就完了
That's it?
他杀了卡里尔
After he killed Khalil?
斯塔尔 一定会有全面的调查
Starr, there will be a full investigation.
警察调查警察 是么
Cops investigating cops, huh?
你清楚他们应该会以谋杀罪起诉那个种族歧视的家伙的
You know they should've charged his racist ass with murder.
但是这不可能 对吗 卡洛斯叔叔
But that ain't gonna happen, is it, Uncle Carlos?
这名警官以前
Nothing like this has ever happened
从未出过这种事
with this officer before.
哦 初犯 让我们从轻发落吧
Oh, first-timer. Let's cut him a break.
卡洛斯 你会参与调查的 是吗
Carlos, you're gonna help with the investigation, right?
我不行 这种事一般交给地方检察院处理
I can't. We hand situations like this over to the DA.
让陪审团来处理
We headed for a grand jury?
很有可能
Most likely.
让我猜猜看 他们会要求斯塔尔出庭作证
And let me guess, they gonna ask Starr to testify.
不 不 不 不 不 我不想让大家
No, no, no, no, no. I don't want everyone
知道斯塔尔是目击证人
knowing that Starr is the witness.
她不需要这样的关注 不
She doesn't need that kind of attention.
我们是不是该请律师
No! Should we get a lawyer?
目击者不需要请律师
Witnesses don't need attorneys.
斯塔尔不只是目击者 卡洛斯
Starr ain't just a witness, 'Los.
听着 如果你不信任法律系统
Look, if you don't trust the system,
你至少该相信我
can you at least trust me?
- 斯塔尔就像是我的亲女儿 - 可她并不是
- Starr is like my daughter. - But she ain't.
你被抓起来的时候我一直把她当自己的女儿
It didn't seem that way when you was locked up.
别吵了 你们俩
Stop it! Both of you!
陪审团意味着什么
What does a grand jury mean?
陪审团
Grand jury.
这种事就会闹到新闻上
Stuff like this ends up on the news.
人们会受到死亡威胁
People get death threats.
为卡里尔伸张正义
警察会盯着你
Cops target them.
在学校会怎么样
What will it mean at school?
我会不会变成贫民区来的穷孩子
Will I suddenly be the poor girl from the hood
目击了她的朋友被杀
who saw her friend get killed?
我一定要保持沉默
I just gotta be quiet.
你能多给我一点鸡肉吗
Can you just give me more chicken?
- 斯塔尔 空位 - 斯塔尔
- Starr, open! - Starr!
斯塔尔 快传
Starr, pass it!
见鬼
Damn!
斯塔尔 你就当做篮球是一块炸鸡
Starr, just pretend the ball is a piece of fried chicken!
- 你说什么 - 怎么了 就垃圾话而已
- What was that? - What? It's game talk.
炸鸡也算垃圾话
Fried chicken is game talk?
我可从来没听人用过
I've never heard that one before.
我的天 斯塔尔 我们午饭就吃的炸鸡
Holy shit. Starr, we had fried chicken for lunch?
我开玩笑的
I-It was a joke.
好吧
Okay.
慢着 出什么事了 亲爱的
Wait. What's going on, girl?
我是说 我俩
I mean, you know me,
互相了解 胜过任何人
I know you, better than anyone.
你没事吧
You okay?
是啊 是啊 我没事 我就是累了
Yeah. Yeah, I'm fine. I'm just tired.
鲁本烧烤 肋排 鸡肉 牛肉 猪肉 火鸡
好了 我把你爸点的香肠放在烤炉里了
All right. Imma put Mav's hot links on the grill.
项上烤焦 边上烤脆
Little burnt on top and crusty on the side.
你们先吃点蛋糕等等吧
Y'all go ahead and take some pound cake while y'all wait.
- 谢谢 鲁本先生 - 谢谢 鲁本先生
- Thanks, Mr. Reuben. - Thank you, Mr. Reuben.
一名17岁的黑人少年
...17-year-old black teenager
被一名白人警官于周六晚上枪杀
by a white police officer Saturday night.
我们已经得到了最新信息
New information is being released
关于卡里尔·哈里斯枪杀案
regarding the shooting death of Khalil Harris.
行车记录仪的影像显示 警官以为
Dashcam footage, where the officer thought
突发新闻 卡里尔·哈里斯枪击案
他去拿武器
he was going for a weapon
其实只是一把毛刷而并非手枪
shows it was not a gun but a hairbrush.
我儿子什么错也没有犯
My son ain't never done nothing wrong!
卡里尔是个好孩子
- Khalil was a good boy! - Mm-hmm.
卡里尔·哈里斯母亲哭诉 布伦达·哈里斯
他们为什么要那样对他
Why'd they have to do that to hi?
这到底是为什么
What this hae to happen fo?
怎么 他就不能一边走在路上
What, he can't even walk down the stret
一边梳头吗
and brush his damn hai?
他们为什么要让布伦达夫人上电视
I mean, why would they put Miss Brenda on TV like that?
枪击案有一名目击者
There's a witness to the shooting
将会被传唤至陪审团前作证
who'll be called to testify in front of the grand jury.
社区领导正在进行抗议
Community leaders are up in arms...
你现在是名人了啊
So you famous now.
什么
What?
我看到你和卡里尔一起走的
I saw you leave with Khalil.
你现在一副紧张担心的样子
Now you all jittery and jumpy and shit.
是你吧 斯塔尔
It's you, Starr.
别骗我
Don't even lie.
你准备好大闹一场了吗
You ready to stir some shit up?
什么意思
What you mean?
你在现场 你会告诉大家
Well, you was there, so you gotta tell everybody
当时发生的事情
what happened.
你会站出来为卡里尔说话 对吧
You're gonna stand up for Khalil, right?
听着 不能只让布伦达一个人站出来发声
Listen, Brenda can't be the only one talking.
你清楚卡里尔会站出来替你说话的
You know Khalil would've stood tall and spoke for you.
嘿 姑娘们
Hey, queens.
嘿 爸爸
Hi, Daddy!
上车吧
Get in the car.
不 我不用了
Nah, I'm good.
我可以送你到你爸店里
I'll take you up to Big Mav's.
上车吧
Get in the car.
慕尚里的商人
Drug dealers in the Mulsanne
站在食物链顶点
At the top of the food chain
深陷毒品 没有帮派
Trappin' the cocaine no gang
无名杀手
Shooter with no name...
花多少钱补给你
Make up for what you spent.
不用 谢谢
No, thanks.
干吗
What?
听说是你在那孩子被杀时候和他在一起
Heard you was with that boy when he got himself killed.
真是惨痛的记忆
Some hard shit to see.
相信我 很难忘掉这种事
Believe me, it's hard to forget, too.
我住在高地一辈子了
I been in the Heights forever.
信我
So trust.
我经历过这样的事
I been where you at.
那种伤痛永远不会消失
Hurt like that don't never leave you.
但是你必须继续努力
But you gotta keep pushing.
你懂我的意思吗
You feel me?
妈妈在家吗
Mama at the house?
不知道 阿叶莎想去哪就去哪
I don't know. Iesha be where she at.
赛文呢
What about Seven?
你爸爸为什么给那孩子起名叫赛文
Why your daddy and Iesha name that boy Seven?
他中间名是什么八吗
What's his middle name? Eight?
卡特杂货店 啤酒 冷饮 面包 小吃 牛奶
嘿 麦弗叔叔
Hey, Uncle Mav.
嘿 肯雅
Hey, Kenya.
你这个老实日子过得如何
How's that domestic life treatin' you?
你去跟阿伊莎结个婚
You go ahead, put a ring on Iesha.
你就知道了
You gonna find out.
看起来生意还不错
Look like business is going well.
我早就该自己把这间店包下来
Guess I should've bought this store for me
而不是给你
instead of you.
可你没有
But you didn't.
我听说了斯塔尔朋友的事情
I heard about Starr's homeboy.
伙计 你知道他们是啥样
Man, you know how they do.
先开枪 再问问题
Shoot first, ask questions later.
你应该让她远离那些麻烦
You really should try and keep her out of trouble.
麻烦
Trouble?
我只想说 我觉得
I'm just saying, I think it's best
她不要去跟警察讲话比较好
if she don't talk to Five-O.
你懂我的意思吗
You feel me?
你不用担心斯塔尔
You ain't got to worry about Starr.
你管好你自己的女儿 我管好我的
You take care of your girl, and I'll handle mine.
就这样挺好
- It's like that? - It's exactly like that.
嘿 斯塔尔
Hey, Starr.
记住我跟你说的话 好吗
Remember what I told you, all right?
把这些事情抛在脑后
You keep that shit in your rearview.
我跟你讲
Mnh-mnh. I'm telling you.
他那是在威胁她
He was threatening her!
他不会伤害她的
He ain't gonna hurt her.
他会的
He will.
如果他认为斯塔尔会告诉警方
If he thinks that Starr is gonna tell the police
卡里尔是为他卖命的 他会的
that Khalil worked for him, he will.
那样怎么办
And then what? Hmm?
他就会逼迫你帮他卖命
He's gonna rope you right back in.
一朝进了王侯帮 一辈子脱不了干系
Once a King Lord, always a King Lord.
我为人顶罪
When you spend three years in lockup
蹲了三年牢房
doing somebody else's time,
我才不会回去
ain't no roping back in.
他让我脱身 我们说好的
He let me out. That was our deal.
麦弗里克
Maverick...
我们得搬家
we're moving.
亲爱的 我们在这边大有发展
Baby, we could do some good stuff around here.
你住在哪里并不能决定你的身份 麦弗里克
Where you live does not define who you are, Maverick.
- 亲爱的 听我说 - 不
- Baby, listen to me... - No!
你听我说
You listen!
为了你的家庭牺牲是应该的
It's okay to make sacrifices for your family.
我的天 你难道以为我妈妈搬家
God! Do you think that my mother moved
带我和卡洛斯离开花园高地
me and Carlos out of Garden Heights
去那所天主教学校
and into that Catholic school
就是为了学习如何祷告吗 不是
so we could learn how to pray? No.
我要确保我的孩子们
I'm gonna make sure that my kids have it
至少得到和我一样的机会
at least as good as I did.
若非如此 那还有什么意义
If not, what's the point?
我们不就是为了这个才送他们去别的学校吗
That's why we have them up there in that school!
那你觉得当他们发现斯塔尔和卡里尔在一起时候
And what do you think that school will do
学校的人会是什么样的反应呢
when they find out that Starr was with Khalil?
那些白人 喜欢说自己
Those white folks, they love to boast
接受种族多样性的家伙
about how diverse that school is,
可你知道
but you know what?
这种多样性他们吃不消的
This is too much diversity for them.
我不太舒服 我不去上学了
I don't feel good, so I'm not going.
没有人舒服 但是我们都要坚持
None of us feel good, Starr, but we're pressing on anyway.
你去换衣服吧
So you go get dressed.
- 我 - 去换衣服
- I... - Go get dressed.
耐克
娜塔莎
- 我可以进来吗 - 嗯
- Can I come in? - Yeah.
没准等我们回家
Maybe when we get back...
可以一起看
we can watch that
哈利·波特与混血幽灵火焰杯
Harry Potter and the Goblet of Half-Blood Gumble Ghosts.
我没事的 爸爸
I think I'm good, Daddy.
和你一起看哈利·波特最没意思了
You the worst person to watch Harry Potter with.
你全程就在说
The whole time you're like,
哈利·波特讲的就是帮派斗争
"Harry Potter is about the gang theory."
确实如此啊
- It is. - Mm-hmm.
霍格沃茨四个学院有自己的颜色
Hogwarts houses have they own colors,
和地盘
they own hideouts, and they always ridin'
一直都在互相伤害
for each other.
怎么不是讲帮派了
How that ain't about gangs?
你知道我说得对
- You know I'm right. - Mm-hmm.
你们自己不也有自己的哈利·波特帮吗
Y'all had y'all's own little Harry Potter gang.
现在娜塔莎和卡里尔都不在了 就剩你了
Now Natasha and Khalil both gone, and you still here.
你要好好珍惜这段时光
Trying to make some sense out of it.
这就是暴徒生活
It's THUG LIFE.
你给婴儿灌输的仇恨
"The Hate U Give Little Infants..."
会毁了所有人
"F's Everybody."
我知道这个缩写
I know what it stands for.
你觉得这代表什么
What do you think it means?
我觉得这不仅仅影响孩子
I think it's about more than just the youth.
我觉得这影响我们大家
I think it's about us.
我们是谁
Us who?
黑人群体
Black people.
穷人 底层人民
Poor people. Everybody at the bottom.
没错 你说对了
Right, you on it.
图帕克曾试图告诉我们
Pac was trying to school us
社会是如何排斥我们的
on how the system's designed against us.
你觉得为什么我们那么多邻居
Why else you think so many people
都贩毒
in our neighborhood deal?
- 因为他们需要钱 - 是啊
- They need the money. - Yeah.
这里根本找不到像样的工作
And there ain't no real jobs around here,
所以他们落入了陷阱
so they fall into the trap.
什么陷阱
What trap?
贩毒是个价值数百亿的营生
Drugs a multi-billion-dollar industry.
我和卡里尔这样的兄弟陷了进去
Brothers like me and Khalil get caught up
因为看起来这可以致富
'cause it look like a way out.
可是毒品都卖进了我们自己人手里
But that shit is flown into our communities...
我也没听说谁赚了大钱买得起私人飞机
and I don't know nobody with a private jet.
- 你呢 - 没
- Do you? - Mnh-mnh.
我也没有
Me neither.
然后他们就害了我们
And then they trap us.
我们进了监狱 又是另一个价值百亿的营生
And we end up in prison, another billion-dollar hustle.
他们抓人就像是
And they got us riding through there
把我们当做传送带上面的货物
like we on a conveyor belt.
我就是这样和我爸爸进了监狱
That's how I end up in prison with my daddy.
你和你爸爸一起进监狱
You went to jail with your own daddy?
是啊
Yep.
但是我和他一起被抓的时候
But when I caught up with him,
他什么也帮不了我
wasn't nothin' he can do to help me.
他不过是一个虚弱年迈又后悔的老头
He was just a weak, old man with regrets.
他的人生那时已经没希望了
And his light was gone.
我发誓我绝不会变成那样
And I swore that would never be me.
因为我要为我的孩子打破这个循环
Because Imma break the cycle for my kids.
我还没准备把卡里尔
I'm not ready to see Khalil
当做一具冰冷的尸首
as a soulless mannequin.
他的嘴唇还有血色
His lips are too pink.
不过他的酒窝不见了
And he doesn't have his dimples.
走吧 亲爱的
Come on, baby.
这不是他 妈妈
It ain't him, Mama.
我知道
I know.
我们有的是时间
We got time.
嘿 你没事吧
Hey, you all right?
它治好了我 我知道有效
'Cause it healed me I know it works
治好了我 永远不会
'Cause it healed me it will never
永远
Never
失去作用
Lose its power
血液还在流淌
The blood still works
我知道血液还在流淌
I know...
你妈妈和王侯帮的人来了
Your mama's here with King.
欧耶 血液还在流淌
Oh, yeah, the blood still works
我知道血液还在流淌
I know the blood still works
赛文
Seven!
是啊 血液还在流淌
Yeah, the blood still works
赛文
Seven!
过来和我们一起
Come on back here with us!
我知道血液还在流淌
I know the blood still works
亲爱的 过去和你妈妈一起
Baby, go back there with your mother.
血液还在流淌
The blood still works
血液还在工作
血液还在流淌
The blood still works...
你知道他不想和她一起
You know he don't want to sit with her.
我知道 但是她在教堂里大吼大叫
I know, but she's yellin' in the church, baby.
失去作用
Lose its power
永远不会
It will never
永远
Never
失去作用
Lose its power
血液还在流淌
The blood still works!
阿门 哈利路亚
Amen! Hallelujah!
阿门 感谢合唱团
Amen! Thank you, choir,
与我们一起祷告
for blessing us
带着如此的
with such wonderful...
虔诚与感恩
praise and worship.
阿门 我的兄弟姐妹们
Amen! Brothers and sisters.
我们这里迎来了一位演讲者
We have a speaker here with us today.
哈里斯一家
The Harris family have asked us all
请求我们听她发言
to listen to what she has to say.
上来吧 爱普尔·奥芙拉姐妹
Come on up, Sister April Ofrah.
我是爱普尔·奥芙拉 来自我们要正义的一名律师
I'm April Ofrah, a lawyr with Just Us For Justic.
在祷告之前 我刚刚得到消息
Just before the service, I was informed
警方无意逮捕
that the police have no intentions
谋害了这位少年的警官
of arresting the officer who murdered this young man.
哪怕有可信的目击者
Despite having a credible eyewitness.
我的天
Oh, my God!
我今天并不想来到这个地方
This is the last place I wanted to be today.
我知道我不是一个人
And I know I'm not alone.
但是 我们还是来了
But here we are agai.
暴力 残暴
Violence, brutalit.
故事都是一样的 只不过发生在不同的人身上
It's the same story, just a different name.
是的 你说的对
Yes. You're right.
今天这事发生在卡里尔·哈里斯身上
Today's name is Khalil Harri.
又是一名无辜的黑人少年 手中未持械
Another unarmed, young, black man.
这告诉我们什么呢
What does that tell us?
沙美尔·贝尔说得最好
Shamell Bell said it best.
我们无法做到手无寸铁
"It is impossible to be unarmed
因为他们把肤色当做威胁
when our blackness is the weapon that they fear."
我拒绝让肤色
And I refuse to let our blackness be seen
被视为武器或者弱点
as a weapon or as a weakness.
- 对 - 对 说得好
- Yeah! - Yeah! That's right!
所以哈里斯一家和我
That is why the Harris family and I ask you
请求大家加入我们
to join us after the service...
前往警察局进行一场和平游行
for a peaceful march past the police station.
分而治之是他们的手段
Division is how they win.
- 他们最怕我们联合起来 - 对
- Unity is how they crumble. - Yeah!
我们在外面见 谢谢大家
See you outside after the service. Thank you.
阿门
Amen!
谢谢
- Thank you! - Whoo!
感谢 奥芙拉姐妹 给我们带来如此
Thank you, Sister Ofrah, for such powerful
激励人心的讲话
and encouraging words.
你看到了吗
Did you see that?
她怎么知道的
How does she even know?
一定是罗萨莉夫人说的
Gotta be Miss Rosalie.
准备加入我们
...to join our sister
一起进行和平游行 为了正义
in her peaceful march for justice!
不只是为了卡里尔 也是为了我们大家
Not only for Brother Khalil, but for all of us!
卡里尔的血不会白流
Khalil's life will not be in vain!
说得没错
That's right!
是啊 哈利路亚
Yeah! Hallelujah!
我们要什么
What do we want?
为卡里尔伸张正义
Justice for Khalil!
- 什么时候要 - 现在
- When do we want it? - Now!
- 我们要什么 - 为卡里尔伸张正义
- What do we want? - Justice for Khalil!
什么时候要 现在
- When do we want it? - Now!
我们要什么 为卡里尔伸张正义
- What do we want? - Justice for Khalil!
什么时候要 现在
- When do we want it? - Now!
我们要什么 为卡里尔伸张正义
- What do we want? - Justice for Khalil!
什么时候要 现在
- When do we want it? - Now!
我们要什么 为卡里尔伸张正义
- What do we want? - Justice for Khalil!
什么时候要 现在
- When do we want it? - Now!
我们要什么 为卡里尔伸张正义
- What do we want? - Justice for Khalil!
什么时候要 现在
- When do we want it? - Now!
我们要什么 为卡里尔伸张正义
- What do we want? - Justice for Khalil!
什么时候要 现在
- When do we want it? - Now!
我们要什么 为卡里尔伸张正义
- What do we want? - Justice for Khalil!
我们要正义
什么时候要 现在
- When do we want it? - Now!
我们要什么 为卡里尔伸张正义
- What do we want? - Justice for Khalil!
什么时候要 现在
- When do we want it? - Now!
我们要什么 为卡里尔伸张正义
- What do we want? - Justice for Khalil!
什么时候要 现在
- When do we want it? - Now!
我们要什么 为卡里尔伸张正义
- What do we want? - Justice for Khalil!
什么时候要 现在
- When do we want it? - Now!
我们要什么 为卡里尔伸张正义
- What do we want? - Justice for Khalil!
什么时候要 现在
- When do we want it? - Now!
记住 这是和平示威
Remember, this is a peaceful protest!
我可不这么觉得
I ain't too sure about that.
别碰我
Boy, don't put your hands on me!
这是和平示威
This is a peaceful protest!
你居然推她
You pushed her!
- 没有正义就不和平 - 不要种族歧视警察
- No justice, no peace! - No racist police!
没有正义就不和平 不要种族歧视的警察
No justice, no peace! No racist police!
好了 我们得离开
All right, we gotta leave.
没有正义就不和平
No justice, no peace!
我们走
Let's go!
不要种族歧视的警察
No racist police!
没有正义就不和平 不要种族歧视的警察
No justice, no peace...
嘿 赛文
Hey, Seven!
走吧
Come on.
你在说什么呢
What the hell you talkin' about?
没有正义就不和平  不要种族歧视的警察
No justice, no peace! No racist police!
没有正义就不和平 不要种族歧视的警察
没有正义就不和平
No justice, no peace!
在花园高地
A protest took place
举行了一次游行示威
in the neighborhood of Garden Heights
就在卡里尔·哈里斯的葬礼之后
following the funeral of Khalil Harris,
一位黑人青年被警官枪杀
a young black man who was killed by a police officer.
虽然起初是一场和平示威
And though the protest started peacefully,
但是很快变成一场
it quickly turned violent
与警方的暴力斗殴
as protesters and police clashed.
此次抗议起因是
This comes after no charges were brought forward
涉案警官没有受到任何起诉
against the police officer
而只是面临停职留薪的处罚
who has been placed on administrative leave
检察院要评估各项证据再立案
until all the evidence can be evaluated.
突发新闻 布莱恩·麦金塔警官
我们带您回顾今天晚间早先的报道
We now take you to coverage from earlier this evening.
我正在和抗议者
I'm here with the protesters
一起前往警察局
on the way to the police station.
那个警察无缘无故
That cop shot that boy in cold blood
就枪杀了那孩子
for no damn reason!
无辜的黑人 一次又一次的
Innocent black men keep getting killed
遭到警察杀害
by the police time and time again,
这是不对的
and it ain't right!
整个体系都腐败透顶
The whole damn system is corrupt as hell.
正如大家所见
As you can see,
花园高地的人们群情激奋
emotions are high here in Garden Heights.
这里的人们因为卡里尔的遭遇感到十分愤慨
The community is outraged with what has been happening,
他们在寻求正义
and they are seeking justice.
直播 警察
子弹是不长眼睛的
Bullets don't know where they supposed to go.
嘿 妈妈
Hey, Mama,
他们生气是因为卡里尔死了吗
are they mad 'cause Khalil died?
是啊 宝贝 我们都是为了这个
Yeah, baby. We all are.
塔米尔·莱斯 2014年
桑德拉·布兰德 2015年
埃里克·加纳 2014年
艾米特·提尔 1955年
一条笔记 72个赞 15转发
海莉72 我的天 真的吗 斯塔尔
就是这样 他们怕我们
That's what's up! They're afraid of us, y'all!
克里斯
嘿
Hey.
你和你家人安全吗
Are you and your family safe?
我在看新闻
I'm watching the news.
恩 恩 我们没事 我们很安全
Yeah. Yeah, we're fine. We're completely safe.
你确定吗
You sure?
麦弗里克 别开门
Maverick, don't answer it.
我得挂了
I gotta go.
等一下 斯塔尔
Hold on, Starr.
斯塔尔
Starr.
谁呀
Who is it?
- 你好 - 你好
- Hi. - Hello.
我能进来吗
Can I come in?
警方正在调查
As police are investigating
一次常规停车询问如何演变成
the routine traffic stop that turned...
卡里尔自己不能辩护
Khalil can't speak for himself.
他需要有人替他说话 就是斯塔尔
He needs a voice. Starr is it.
我不喜欢你这个说法
I don't like this already.
丽莎 听她说完
Lisa, just hear her on out.
斯塔尔 你明白陪审团是什么吗
Starr, do you understand what a grand jury is?
是的 就是他们决定
Yeah. It's where they decide
一个人是否需要受审的地方
if somebody should go to trial.
没错 就是他们决定
Right. It's when they decide
是否需要指控麦金塔警官
if charges should be brought against Officer Macintosh.
他们会指控他吗
Will they indict him?
99%的情况他们会的
99 percent of the time, the grand jury indicts.
那剩下百分之一呢
What about that one percent they don't?
那些案子通常都和警察有关
Those cases almost always involve a cop.
但是这次不一样
But that won't happen this time,
当时的情况我看的一清二楚
because I saw everything.
卡里尔被枪杀时 你具体在什么地方
When Khalil was shot, where were you exactly?
在副驾驶座上
In the passenger seat.
你有任何证据证明你看到的事情吗
Do you have any proof of what you saw?
比如你用手机录下了吗
Like, did you record it on a phone?
没 警察让我把手机放下
Nah, the officer told me to drop it.
所以卡里尔没机会在法庭上讨回公道
So Khalil will never have his day in court?
就因为杀他的是警察
All 'cause a cop shot him?
这就是为什么我们要马上审判他
That's why our trial begins now.
在街头 在媒体上
On the streets, in the media.
斯塔尔是卡里尔的唯-一人证
Starr is Khalil's only witness.
好吧
All right.
我们该怎么做
Where do we start?
先接受电视台采访
With a TV interview.
不
No.
我知道你在争取什么 我要保护我女儿
I know what you're fighting for, but I fight for Starr.
我不能让她冒险
And I won't put her at risk.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我另一位好朋友
My other best friend was murdered
在我们十岁那年被杀了
when we were both ten.
我们在街边玩篮球
We were playing basketball on the sidewalk.
有辆车路过
When this car rolled by...
一只带着刺青的手伸了出来
and this tatted hand pulled out a gun.
我们一定是挡了路
We must have been in the way.
他开了三枪
It was three shots.
她倒在了地上
And she was on the ground.
我记得
And I remember...
我记得她看起来很害怕
I remember she looked really scared...
因为她即将看到死后的世界
because she was about to see what happens after you die.
我知道是谁干的
And I know who did it.
什么
What?
斯塔尔 你从没告诉过我们
Starr, you never told us that.
是王侯帮的人
It was a King Lord.
他没有打中我
He missed me once...
我不想给他机会再来杀我
and I didn't want to give him another chance,
于是我就没有说
so I didn't snitch.
几个月后我听说他被杀了
And then I heard a few months later that he got killed.
于是我就什么都没说
So I didn't say anything.
你告诉我 奥芙拉女士
Now tell me, Miss Ofrah...
我这样算什么朋友
what kind of friend is that?
你不能责怪自己 斯塔尔
You can't blame yourself for that, Starr.
你当时太小了
You were young.
你现在也还小
You are young.
我想为了卡里尔 变成更好
I wanna be a better friend for Khalil.
但是上电视这事情
But goin' on TV...
我不是很确定
I don't know about all that.
如果你需要法律咨询
Well, if you ever need legal advice or...
或者是改变了主意
you change your mind...
找我
I'm here.
谢谢你
Thank you.
威廉姆森学校
不用上课了 伙计们 走啊
No, school, guys! Come on!
哟 快走 快走
Let's go! Yo, let's go!
我们走
Let's go!
别在大厅里乱跑
Don't run in the halls!
杰克逊 慢点
Jackson, slow it down!
嘿 出什么事了
Hey, what is going on?
不上课 要去游行
School's out. Protesting's in.
我本来都准备好今早的历史测试了
And I was so ready for that history test this morning.
嘿
Hey!
你去哪了
Where have you been?
所有人都翘课了 我们走吧
Everyone's ditching, girl. Come on, let's go.
为卡里尔伸张正义
真不要 我以为你喜欢这种事
Really? I thought you'd love this
考虑到你最近在汤博乐上发的东西
considering what you've been putting up on Tumblr lately.
喜欢
- Love it? - Well...
不是喜欢啦
Not love it obviously,
但是 你关心这些事 对吧
but, I mean, you care, right?
这是你家那边的事情
It's your neighborhood.
我想你没准认识他
I thought you might even know the guy.
我只是不觉得用这种事做借口
I just don't think it's, you know, cool
来翘课是件很光彩的事情
to use the situation as an excuse to skip class.
怎么啦 斯塔尔
What the hell, Starr?
这不仅是翘课的理由
It's not just an excuse to skip class.
这是伸张正义
It's a good cause.
同时也恰好是不上学的
It also happens to be a really good excuse
好理由
to cut school.
我今天真不想见到我们数学老师的脸
I really don't want to see our math teacher's face today.
你呢
Do you?
每个人
Everybody people
都会流血 每个人 都有需求
Everybody bleed, everybody need something
每个人爱
Everybody love
每个人知道
Everybody know...
慢着 你去了哪里
...where you been? Bitch I been in
这只不过是个开始
This is merely the beginning again
你都住在哪里
What you been living in?
为卡里尔伸张正义 黑人命也贵重
为卡里尔伸张正义
Justice for Khalil!
怎么 怎么啦
What? What's wrong?
这不对
This isn't right.
不然还有谁会为了我们的人讲话
Who else is gonna speak up for our people, girl?
我们的人
Our people?
你要去哪儿
Where are you going?
黑人命也贵重
斯塔尔
Starr?
我到处在找你
I've been looking for you everywhere.
我不舒服 我要回家
I don't feel well. I'm going home.
出什么事了
What's wrong?
嘿
Hey.
你认识他 对不对
You knew him, didn't you?
那个被害的孩子
The kid who got killed.
不 给我点空间 好吗
Nah. Just give me some space, okay?
你为什么不肯告诉我出什么事了
Why won't you tell me what's going on?
斯塔尔
Starr?
嘿 你能来接我吗
Hey. Can you come get me?
嘿 嘿
- Hey. - Hey.
抽筋
Cramps, huh?
是啊 人就是会抽筋的嘛
Yeah. People cramps.
弗里蒙特纪念医院
- 好好的 - 谢谢 叔叔
- Be well. - Thanks, Unc.
就因为一些愚蠢的
So, just 'cause some dumb,
白人学生翘了课
privileged white kids skip class,
你就觉得你也可以翘课了
you think it's okay for you to leave school too?
你猜怎么 斯塔尔
Well, guess what, Starr.
- 翘课就翘课呗 - 我知道 妈妈
- It is what it is. - I know, Mama.
可他们表现的就好像卡里尔的死
But they're acting like Khalil was murdered
只是用来翘掉化学测试的借口
just so that they can skip a chem test.
而我却没为他的死做任何事
And I didn't do anything about it.
妈妈
Mama...
我要为他说话
I need to speak for him.
我猜你就是斯塔尔
Let me guess. You're Starr.
是的
Yeah.
斯塔尔 很感谢你能鼓起勇气为卡里尔发声
Starr, thank you so much for having the courage to do this.
不客气
You're welcome.
戴安很激动能请到你
Diane's very excited to have you.
我们为了让你上直播
We even bumped a segment
还取消了另一个节目
to make sure yours airs tonight.
你保证答应我们的事情要做到
And you're sure the thing we talked about is happening?
直达顶层
都安排好了
It's arranged.
他们同意对斯塔尔的脸部作模糊处理
They've agreed to blur Starr's face.
看的人不会认出是她
No one watching will ever know it's her.
你是本次枪击案唯一的目击者
You are the only witness to the shooting death
一名没有武器的黑人青年被警察枪杀
of a young, unarmed black man by a police officer.
现在全国数百万观众
Now, millions of people across the country
都听说了卡里尔·哈里斯的名字
have heard the name Khalil Harris.
他和你是什么关系呢
Who was he to you?
我们从小就认识了
We knew each other since we were babies
不过如果是他在这里 他大概会说
but if he was here, he would probably say...
他比我大五个月 两周
that he was actually five months, two weeks,
零一天
and one day older than me.
他还是个孩子
He was a kid.
没错
Yep.
你怎么样想那些
What do you think about the people
只关注卡里尔不好的一面的人
that are only focusing on the not-so-good aspects of Khalil?
关注他贩毒的人
That he sold drugs.
如果他们知道原因
Well, if they knew why,
他们就不会那么说他了
then they wouldn't talk about him like that.
他为什么要贩毒呢
Why did he sell them?
卡里尔的妈妈很爱他 但是她有毒瘾
Khalil's mom loved him, but she was an addict
所以没人可以挣钱
so there was no one to bring in money
没人照顾他的弟弟
to help his little brother...
他的奶奶得了癌症
and his grandma who has cancer.
他唯一的选择
So he had to take the only available jb
就是这份工作
in the neighborhod
才可以给他足够的钱养家
that would pay him enouh to help them.
什么工作
Available job?
为花园高地最大的毒贩组织卖命
Dealing for the biggest drug dealers in Garden Heights.
王候帮
The King Lords.
所以有一家帮派
So there's one gang
掌控了你家周围
that controls your entire neighborhood?
跟我讲讲
Tell me about that.
你为什么只关心这些事情
Why are you only asking me about that?
我下周就要被
I mean, next week, I'll be called to testify
传唤到陪审团前作证
in a grand jury investigation,
但是没有人想知道究竟发生了什么事
but no one wants to know what actually happened.
每个人都想知道卡里尔做了什么
Everyone wants to know what Khalil did.
说了什么 没有做什么
What he said, what he didn't do.
就好像这是他的错
Like it's his fault.
我没听说过还能指控死了的人
I didn't know that a dead person
犯下谋杀案
could be charged with his own murder.
如果麦金塔警官坐在这里
If Officer Macintosh were sitting here now...
你会对他说什么
what would you say to him?
我会问他 他是不是后悔没把我也杀掉
I'd ask him if he wished that he shot me too.
黑人食物
来啦 进来吗 兄弟
- Here we go! - Checkin' in, bro?
是啊 应该吧 确实有道理
Yeah. I might. Yeah, it makes sense.
我知道
I know.
你还需要什么吗
Y'all need anything else?
不 我们应该都有了
Nah, I think we got everything we need right here.
你俩有必要这样秀恩爱吗
Y'all really gotta be booed up like that?
你以为我怎么追上她的
How else you think I pulled her?
我知道
I know how.
妈妈
Mama!
看到没 我们可不想看你们这样
See, we did not need all of that.
我都吓死了
I'm scarred for life.
好了 大家手握好
All right, y'all, circle up.
好了
All right.
感谢上帝赐予我们家庭
Dear Heavenly Father, thank you for blessing this food
这丰盛的晚餐
- and this family. - Hmm.
感谢您帮助斯塔尔散发光芒
And thank you for allowing Starr to shine today.
愿主保佑她能够专心学业
Yes, Lord, and please help her stay focused on her studies.
为了家人感谢您
Thank you for my family.
我本来打算这么说的
That's what I was gonna say.
我也是
Me too.
阿门
Amen.
阿门 阿门
- Amen. - Amen.
- 阿门 - 先吃菜 小子
- Amen. - Eat the greens first, man.
嘿 我要那个辣酱
- Hey. - Need that hot sauce.
- 蔬莱 - 想想吧
- Vegetables. - Think about it...
- 蔬莱 蔬菜 - 至少
- Vegetables. - ...at least.
和辣酱比吗 是啊
- And compare it to the hot sauce? - Yeah...
不行
No. Mnh-mnh.
我喜欢塔巴斯科辣酱
I like the Tabasco.
你要像平常一样要加糖吗
Are you gonna ask for more sugar, like always?
好吃
It's really good.
你们为什么要担心我吃糖
Why are you worried about my sugar?
让我尝尝
Let me taste that.
看 你放了辣酱
See, you put hot sauce.
我就说需要塔巴斯科辣酱
That's why I said it needs Tabasco.
是啊
Yeah.
这个根本不够辣
This ain't hot enough right here.
我会尝尝的
I'll try it though.
怎么 你不想吃吗 亲爱的 你就尝一口
What, you don't want to, baby? Put a little bit of the yam.
丽莎
Lisa.
待在这里
Stay here.
嘿 斯塔尔今天做了件蠢事
Hey, Starr did some real stupid shit today.
你少提我孩子的名字 国王
Keep my kids out your mouth, King.
你这倔驴是不是欠教训
Your hard head makes for a soft ass whoopin'.
你这是来自讨苦吃的
You comin' close to gettin' your own.
你怎么不试试啊
Well, why don't you try it?
别动
Stay!
嘿 你怎么不
Hey, why don't you...
弗里蒙特警察
嘿 走了
Hey, come on!
有什么问题吗
You got a problem here?
没有 警官
No, sir, Officer.
那你在做什么
What was that?
我只是在和我家人吃饭
I'm just having dinner with my family.
然后就出来买毒品了
Until you came out to score?
好了 过来 跟我来
All right, come on. Let's go.
靠墙站着
Lean against the wall.
没事的 瑟卡尼
It's okay, Sekani.
斯塔尔 深呼吸 深呼吸 没事的 亲爱的
Starr, you breathe. Just breathe, okay, baby?
- 好了 他没武器 - 把你身份证拿出来
- All right, he's clean. - Take out your ID.
- 我太太拿着我的钱包 - 你太太在哪
- My wife has my wallet. - Where is she?
拿我的钱包来
Get my wallet!
- 别过来 - 爸爸
- Stop. - Daddy?
没事的
It's okay!
好了 就在我这呢 警官
All right, I got it right here, Officer.
麦弗里克·卡特 听着耳熟么
Maverick Carter. Sound familiar?
进去待着吧
Go back inside now.
不 谢谢 警官 我要在这里
No, thank you, Officer. I will wait right here
等到你放我丈夫走
until you release my husband.
我说了进去待着
I said go back inside.
不 警官 我爸爸什么也没有做
No, sir. My father didn't do anything wrong.
- 给我看你的身份证 - 他还是个孩子
- Show me your ID. - He is a child!
你想看他的学生证
Do you want to see his school ID
还是他的驾驶证
or his learner's permit?
夫人 回里面去
Ma'am, go back inside...
- 他什么也没有做 - 好了 够了
- He didn't do anything! - All right, that's it.
我知道你看到那辆车开走了
I know you saw that car drive away.
I know you saw that car drive off.
你看到那个家伙开走了
You saw that guy drive off!
你怎么不去找他啊
Why don't you talk to him, huh?
不 不 瑟卡尼 回去
No! No! Sekani, go inside!
把手机放下 快点
Put that down, now!
我有权记录这一切
I have a right to record this.
她是那名证人
She's the witness.
是啊 我们都看到了 我们的手机也都在拍
Yeah, we see y'all. And all these cameras do, too!
有本事就让大家见识一下 你们是怎么对我们的
Go on and show everybody how y'all really treat us.
我们走
Let's go.
就当我们给你的警告
Consider this a warning.
你没事吧 没事吧
You okay? You okay?
都去拿东西 我们回家
Y'all get y'all stuff and let's go.
好 好 好 好
Okay.
你没事吧
You okay?
你没事吧 好了 走吧
You okay? All right, come on.
走吧 我们去接瑟卡尼
Come on. Let's get Sekani.
哦 亲爱的
Oh, baby.
我很抱歉 爸爸
I'm so sorry, Daddy.
这是我的错
This is my fault.
我不该上电视的
I never should have gone on TV.
我该选择沉默的
I should've stayed quiet.
所有人都下车
Everybody, get up out the car.
下车到草地上站成一排
Get out the car and line up on the grass.
十项原则第七项 背
Point seven of the Ten-Point Program. Say it.
别哭了 背出来
Stop crying and say it!
我们要求立即停止警察暴力
"We want an immediate end to police brutality."
背完
Finish it.
停止谋杀黑人
"And the murder of Black people
及其他有色人种和弱势群体
and people of color and oppressed people."
用什么办法 用一切必要的办法
- By what means? - By any means necessary.
那你为什么要保持沉默
So why you gonna be quiet?
我纹身写的什么
What does that say?
为何而生 为何而死
"Reasons to live. Give reasons to die."
是啊
Yeah.
你 你的哥哥弟弟
You, your brothers...
你的妈妈
and your mother...
都是我活着和死去的理由
are my reasons to live and die.
我在你们的名字里赋予了力量
I gave each of you power in your names.
赛文 完美
Seven: perfection.
斯塔尔 光芒
Starr: light.
瑟卡尼 欢乐
Sekani: joy.
使用它
Use it!
当你打算讲话
So when you ready to talk...
就去讲
you talk.
不要别人让你禁声你就禁声
Don't ever let nobody make you be quiet.
你在逗我吗
Are you kidding me?
不 不 不 慢 慢 慢
No, no, no! Wait, wait, wait!
芝加哥公牛 克利夫兰骑士
三分球
Three-pointer!
我的天
Oh, my gosh.
你太弱了 随便吧
You suck. Whatever.
你别逗我了
Are you kidding me?
我肯定虐你
I'm going to get you.
怎么了
What's up with you?
没事
Nothing.
怎么 是我小题大做了
What, so I'm trippin'?
我们来这里之后你一共说了不到五个字
You haven't said more than five words since we got here.
我现在就有说啊
I'm talking right now.
你还想让我说什么呢
What more do you want me to say?
我们还是看电视吧
Why don't we just go back to the TV?
来电者必须年满18岁
Callers eligible must be 18 or older.
在枪击案发生后
...after the shooting...
警官被指控枪击卡里尔·哈里斯
布莱恩·麦金塔
等一下 能看上一个频道吗
Wait, can you go back?
小布莱恩·麦金塔警官
Officer Brian Macintosh Junior
已经工作五年
has been on the force for five years.
花园高地陷入混乱
在花园高地工作过的大部分人
A majority of those years serving in Garden Heights,
花园高地 万寿菊大道
都清楚此地犯罪率居高不下
known for its high crime rate,
今年的杀人案增长了15%
with murders up 15 percent this year alone.
警官多年来都在进行高危执法
Officers have struggled for years to rein in the violence.
政策的改变
Changes in policies,
黑帮及毒品问题
gangs, and drugs have remained an issue
都是这个黑人聚集地面临的巨大挑战
for this predominantly African American community.
布莱恩是个好孩子
Brian is a good boy.
人们都把他当做了一个怪物
People, they're making him out to be a monster.
被指控警察的父亲
他不敢出门
He's afraid to go out in public,
连买牛奶都不敢去
even for a gallon of milk.
有很多针对他的人身威胁
There's been threats against his life.
针对我们一家的威胁
Our family's lives.
哇 太惨了
Wow. That sucks.
这家人真可怜
That poor family.
什么
What?
他儿子只是在努力工作保护自己
His son was only trying to do his job and protect himself.
他的命也重要的 你知道的
His life matters too, you know.
好吧 呃
Okay, um...
我得去
I need to...
嗯
Yeah.
哇 你们还没有讨论完这件事呢
Whoa. You guys haven't figured this out yet?
等一下 斯塔尔 斯塔尔
Wait. Starr. Starr!
玛雅 我现在没法跟她说话
Maya, I cannot talk to her right now.
那个警察的命也重要
That cop's life matters also.
你就因为我说了这句话生气吗
Are you gonna be mad because I said that, too?
是啊
Yeah.
因为你觉得他的生命
Because you think that his life matters more
要比你说你要帮助抗议的那个人还重要
than the person that you said you were protesting for.
那就有问题
That's a problem.
什么问题
Problem?
好了 你们别吵了
Please, guys, come on.
抗议之后你就取关了我的汤博乐
You unfollowed my Tumblr after the protest.
为什么
Why?
是因为那张艾米特·提尔的照片吗
Was it the picture of Emmett Till that did it?
你有没有在看不下去之前
Did you sympathize with his poor family
心疼一下他家人呢
before you looked away?
好了 玛雅 她现在说我是种族歧视
Okay. Maya, now she's calling me a racist.
不 我没有
Nah, I didn't.
我只是问了你一个问题
I just asked you a question.
难以置信
Unbelievable.
你知道吗
You know what?
我现在已经不认识你是谁了 斯塔尔
I don't know who the hell you are anymore, Starr.
这才是我取关你的原因
That's the real reason I unfollowed you.
哈里斯 你确定我不能接你去舞会吗
该死
Damn.
你穿黑色准没错的
You can never go wrong with black.
永远都是那么优雅
It is always so elegant.
不骗你
I swear.
你肯定会在舞会上美美的
You are gonna look so beautiful for prom.
怎么了 宝贝 跟我说说
What's wrong, munch? Talk to me.
就是我和海莉吵了一架
It's just me and Hailey got into it.
妈妈
Mama?
- 怎么了 - 你从来就没喜欢过她
- What? - You never liked her.
不 我没有
No. That's not true.
我只是不喜欢你跟在她屁股后面的样子
I never liked how you followed her around
就好像你自己没有主见
like you can't think for yourself.
这是有区别的
There's a difference.
比如那次你求我
Like the time that you begged me
把你的头发染紫 对吧
to dye your hair purple. Yeah.
我喜欢紫色头发
I wanted to have purple hair.
不 不 不
No, no, no.
不 为什么
No! Why?
到底为什么
The real why.
因为海莉想要她 我还有玛雅
Because Hailey wanted me, her, and Maya
染同一个颜色
to have matching hair at school.
我就是这个意思 谢谢 就这样
That's what I'm talking about. Thank you. Right there.
好了 那你们之间又怎么了
All right, so what happened between y'all now?
就是她说的一些话
It's just some of the stuff she says. It's like...
让我在想
It makes me wonder how
我们当初到底是怎么做朋友的
we're even friends in the first place.
那这种事 你知道吗
Now that's something, you know what,
你得好好问问自己
you need to ask yourself.
到底这段友谊值不值得
If this friendship is even worth it.
我就是生气我不知道
I'm just so mad that I don't know.
不 不 不 等一下 你可没时间生气
No, no, no. Wait a minute. You don't have time to be mad.
你学业都没跟上
You're behind in your schoolwork.
你还没准备好考SAT（高考）
You... You ain't ready for your SATs.
你要原谅她 然后继续生活
You need to just forgive and you move on.
你就是这样原谅爸爸的吗
Is that what you did with Daddy?
在他把阿伊莎搞怀孕之后
After he got Iesha pregnant with Seven?
你就原谅他继续生活了吗
You just forgave and you moved on?
是的
Yeah.
我就这样做了
Yeah, I did.
这很不容易
It wasn't easy.
虽然我和你爸爸曾经分过手
And even though your dad and I had been broken up
因为阿伊莎那件事 现在都很难释怀
when he got tangled up with Iesha, it still hurt.
但是你知道吗 我必须做决定 我
But you know what? I had to decide. Me.
就是我对你爸爸的爱到底能不能胜过他的错误
If my love for your dad was bigger than his mistakes.
而我对你爸爸的爱
The love that I share with your dad?
足以
That...
足以胜过任何事
That is bigger than everything.
哪怕是和疯子阿伊莎
Even with crazy Iesha?
是的 哪怕是和她
Yeah. Even with crazy Iesha.
听着 亲爱的 如果好的一面可以抵消坏的
Listen, baby, if the good outweighs the bad,
那就把海莉留在你生活中
then you keep Hailey in your life.
如果不然
But if it doesn't...
就让她走吧
you let her go.
威廉姆森学校
威廉姆森毕业舞会
嘿
Hey.
这是你 对吧
It's you, right?
你跟我说你不认识卡里尔
You told me you didn't know Khalil.
是啊 我认识他
Yeah, I knew him.
你以为我不会发现吗
Did you not think that I was gonna find out?
你就打算把一切都瞒着我吗
Were you just gonna hide everything from me?
不是这样的
It's not like that.
斯塔尔 我是你男朋友 这是我的责任
Starr, I'm your boyfriend. That's what I'm here for.
并不是因为我不信任你
It's not like I don't trust you.
那是为什么 告诉我 拜托了
Then what's it like? Tell me. Please.
克里斯 我不住在威廉姆森
Chris, I don't live at Williamson.
如果我告诉每个人
If I had told everybody...
我就会变成亲眼目睹自己朋友遭到杀害的穷孩子
I would've been "poor Starr" who saw her friend get killed.
或者是受人施舍的贫民区孩子
Or "Starr the charity case" who lives in the ghetto.
你真觉得大家在乎你住在哪吗
Do you think people really care about where you live?
是的 我觉得
Yeah, I do.
老天
Geez.
你有见过人死吗
Have you ever seen somebody die?
没有
No.
我见过两次了
Well, I have twice now.
这就是为什么我父母送我和哥哥来这里上学
That's why my parents put me and my brothers in Williamson.
为了保护我们
To protect us.
而现在
And now...
我每天都要隐藏自己
it's like I have to hide who I am every single day.
当我在家 我不能像在学校里那样
When I'm at home, I can't be too Williamson.
当我在这里 我不能像在家那样
When I'm here, I can't act too Garden Heights.
卡里尔是我的初恋
Khalil was my first crush.
我的初吻
My first kiss.
而他最近遭遇了很多苦难
And he was going through so much shit...
我甚至都不知道
and I didn't even know...
因为我选择背弃了他
because I turned my back on him.
我背弃了我的同胞
I turned my back on all of my people.
你知道那种感觉吗
Do you even know what that's like?
不知道
No.
我很抱歉 斯塔尔 真的
And I'm sorry, Starr. I really am.
但是黑人 白人
But black, white...
没人在意的 我们都是一样的
nobody gives a shit. We're all the same.
但是我们不一样
But we're not.
你们都学黑人说话
Y'all wanna act black,
但是你们保留着白人的特权
but you get to keep your white privilege.
你们觉得打打篮球
You think playing ball and jumping
玩玩不着调的说唱
in some lame-ass Williamson cypher
就能让你们感受到做黑人的感受
makes you understand what it is to be black?
并不能的
It doesn't.
斯塔尔 我只想说我不在意肤色
Starr, I just told you I don't see color.
我看到人们的本质 我看你也是一样
I see people for who they are. The exact same way I see you.
如果你无视我的肤色 你就没有看清我
If you don't see my blackness, you don't see me.
我有看清你
I see you.
嘿 你们最好别胡闹啊
Hey, y'all better not be doin' nothin'.
- 我的天 - 我没说笑
- Oh, my God. - I ain't playing.
赛文
Seven!
噢 亲爱的
Aw, baby.
我很抱歉搞砸了舞会
I'm sorry prom got ruined.
你在开玩笑么 我根本不在乎舞会
You kidding me? I don't give a shit about prom.
我只在乎我们舞会之后
What I do give a shit about are the burgers
吃的汉堡
we're gonna eat after prom.
还有奶昔
And the milkshake.
还有下一步
And the next part.
什么下一步
What next part?
我要送你回家
I'm gonna take you home...
我要见见你父亲
and I'm gonna meet your father.
那我建议你赶紧染个色
I suggest you get some color real quick.
我内心有肤色的 真心的
I've got color on the inside, where it counts.
好吧 哥们
All right, man.
我应该考验一下
Well, uh, I think it's time
你的黑人知识了
we test your black card.
感恩节吃什么
What you want for Thanksgiving?
甜土豆馅饼
Sweet potato pie...
还是南瓜
or pumpkin?
甜土豆馅饼 吃一整天
Sweet potato pie. All day.
叮叮叮 不错
- Ding! Ding! Ding! - Okay.
- 这才是我男朋友 - 好了 等一下
- That's my baby right there. - Okay. Hold up.
- 他挺懂的 - 我们还没完呢
- He knows what's up. - We're not done.
奶酪通心粉
Mac and cheese.
是正餐还是小菜
Full meal or side dish?
正餐
Full meal.
- 错 错 错 - 什么
- Whomp, whomp, whomp! - What?
奶酪通心粉不是正餐 哥们
Mac and cheese ain't no full meal, man.
盒装的主食啊
- Mnh-mnh. - It's a meal out of a box.
哎 亲爱的 不行啊
Oh, no, baby. No.
是烤箱里拿出来的
It comes out the oven, bubbly,
- 蓬蓬的 上面有点焦 - 教育一下
- cheesy, crispy on top. - ...Yeah. Preach.
通心粉和奶酪是蛋白质
Macaroni and cheese is a protein.
最上面撒上面包屑
You sprinkle breadcrumbs on top of it.
- 面包屑 - 你说什么
- Breadcrumbs? - You have to what?
不 不行 那可不行
Oh, hell no. No. That ain't gonna cut it.
你俩完蛋了 我走了
Y'all both dead. Excuse me.
- 嘿 爸爸 - 你好吗 儿子
- Hey, Pops. - What's up, man?
嘿 多谢你带他们回家
Hey. Thanks for bringing 'em home.
给你
Here you go.
哦 爸爸 他不要小费
Oh, Daddy, he doesn't need a tip.
怎么 你应该给司机付小费的啊
What? You gotta tip the chauffeur.
嘿 小伙子
Hey, man.
你得趁别人偷了你的车之前
You better get out of here
赶紧走
before someone steal your ride.
嘿 进来 进来呀
Hey! Come in! Come in!
嘿 亲爱的 你好
- Hey, baby. - Hi.
克里斯 很高兴终于见到你了
Chris! It's so nice to finally meet you!
舞会怎么样
How was prom?
还不错 我们提早一些离开了
It was good. Yeah. We came back a little early.
这是谁
Who's this?
爸爸 这是克里斯
Daddy, this is Chris.
克里斯是谁
Who's Chris?
克里斯是我的男朋友
Chris is my boyfriend.
你有男朋友了
You got a boyfriend?
那你以为她和谁去参加舞会
Well, who do you think she went to prom with?
很高兴见到你 卡特先生
It's nice to meet you, Mr. Carter.
你找了个白人男朋友
You got a white boyfriend?
爸爸 他不是我的白人男朋友
Uh, Daddy, he's not my white boyfriend.
他就是我男朋友
He's just my boyfriend.
这孩子是白人
That boy is white.
大家肯定都累了
Well, um, I'm sure everybody's tired.
多谢你 克里斯 安全送他们回家
Thank you so much, Chris, for getting 'em home safe.
我跟你说
And you know what? I really look forward
我很期待再次见到你
to seeing more of you soon.
没问题 卡特夫人
- No problem, Mrs. Carter. - Yeah.
晚安 卡特先生
Good night, Mr. Carter.
- 晚安 斯塔尔 - 晚安
- Good night, Starr. - Good night.
好 晚安
Yeah. Good night.
你知道这孩子的事情
You knew about this boy?
你知道这事情
You knew about this?
还有谁知道
Who the hell else knew about this?
慢着
Hold up.
瑟卡尼知道吗
Does Sekani know about this?
你搞什么 斯塔尔
What the hell, Starr?
你找了个白人男朋友 除了我都知道
You got a white boyfriend, everybody know but me?
我想知道为什么
I wonder why that is.
那孩子叫什么来着
What's this boy's name?
克里斯
Chris.
Chris?
那算是哪门子名字
What kinda plain-ass name is that?
女孩通常会找像他们父亲的男孩子
Girls usually go with boys who look like their daddy.
大概我没给你做一个
Guess I ain't set a good example
黑人的好榜样吧
of a black man for you.
是的 你没有
No, you didn't.
你给我做了一个男人的好榜样
You set a good example of what a man should be.
对头
Duh.
如果这个孩子教你说 对头
If this li'l boy got you saying "duh"...
那你可不能要他
he might have to go.
趴下
Get down!
慢着 不 不 不 麦弗里克
Wait! No, no, no! Maverick!
跟斯塔尔说让她闭嘴 贱人
Tell Starr to keep her mouth shut! Damn bitch!
该死
Damn it!
嘿
Hey.
快进屋
Come on inside.
你在做什么 快进来
What are you doing? Come in.
我要回去
I'm goin' back.
什么
What?
没人可以惹我们家人
Nobody messes with my family.
尤其是王候帮那群人
Especially not King's boys.
你家里人都在这里
Your family is here!
而且我们要搬走了
And this family is moving.
我不许你反对了
I don't wanna hear another word about it.
我们要搬家
We're moving!
我和爸爸一起去
I'm going with Daddy.
赛文 回屋子里去
Seven, get back in the house!
麦弗里克 我求求你
Maverick, I am begging you.
别回去 如果王候帮的人找上门怎么办
Don't go back. What if King comes back?
我正指望呢
I hope he does.
麦弗里克 你答应过我
Maverick! Maverick, you promised!
爸爸
Daddy!
卡里尔-哈里斯枪杀案的目击者
The eyewitness to the shooting of Khalil Harris
我们支持警察 我们支持司法系统
弗里蒙特警局抗议升级
将于明天出席陪审团作证
is set to testify tomorrow before the grand jury.
当地社区负责人担心
Local community leaders
目击者出席作证
fear that the testimony of the witness
不仅仅会助长黑帮暴动
will not only increase gang violence
也加剧了当地警方
but also amplify tension between local police
与花园高地社区的紧张关系
and the Garden Heights community.
有人想恐吓你不要出席明天的陪审困
Someone's trying to scare you about the grand jury tomorrow.
吓到你了吗
Did it work?
我们为什么需要
Why do we need a grand jury
陪审团决定是否起诉
to decide if this should go to trial?
有人不觉得杀死卡里尔
Some people don't see what happened
是犯罪
to Khalil as a crime.
他们觉得是例行检查出了岔子而已
They see it as a traffic stop gone wrong.
为什么
How?
警察拦车时
A lot goes through a cop's mind
心里会想很多事情
when they pull someone over.
尤其是当他们
Especially if they have to get into
在争吵
a pissing contest with the driver
为什么拦车的问题上
about why they stopped him.
这就敲响了警钟
It sets off an alarm.
警察会想
The officer thinks...
他们在隐藏什么事情 这车是偷来的吗
"Are they hiding somethin'? Is the car stolen?"
如果有个女孩和你一样坐在副驾驶上面
Now, if there's a girl in the passenger seat like you...
她看起来还好吗 她有没有遭到殴打 遭到强奸
"Does she look all right? Has she been beaten or raped?"
如果他们开始互相聊天
If they start talking to each other
而不是回答警察问题
and not the officer,
我们会觉得他们想干扰我
we figure they might be trying to distract.
他们在车里藏了什么
What are they hiding in the car?
毒品 武器
Drugs? A weapon?
如果司机开始骂警官
Now, if the driver starts to insult the officer,
我们就会尝试口头控制局面
we try to verbally get control of the situation.
但是如果他们不合作
But if they still don't comply,
我们只得动用武力
then we... we have to use force.
但是你们仍不知道他们是否做了坏事
But you still don't know if they did anything wrong.
所以我们要搜身
That's why we search them.
确保他们没有武器
To make sure that they don't have a weapon.
我们查驾照 命令他们不要动
We run their license and instruct them not to move.
但如果他们开了车门
But if they open the door...
或者把身子探进车窗
or reach through an open window...
他们很可能是去取武器
they're probably goin' for a weapon.
所以 如果我觉得我看到了枪
So if I think I see a gun...
我不会犹豫 我会开枪
I don't hesitate. I shoot.
你会开枪
You shoot?
因为你觉得你看到一把枪
Because you think you see a gun?
你不先说点什么 比如把手举起来
You don't say something first? Like, "Put your hands up"?
看情况 是不是晚上 我能不能看清楚
It depends. Is it night? Can I see?
我是不是独自一人执勤
Am I on duty alone?
如果你是在白人社区呢
What if you were in a white neighborhood?
如如果是西装革履的白人
And it was a white man wearing a suit,
开着一辆奔驰
driving a Mercedes?
他也可能是贩毒的 对吧
He could be a drug dealer, right?
是可能
He could.
如果你看到了他
So if you saw him...
把身子探进车窗
reach into the window...
你觉得你看到一把枪
and you thought that you saw a gun...
你会开枪吗
would you shoot him?
还是你会说 把手举起来
Or would you say, "Put your hands up"?
我会说 把手举起来
I'd say, "Put your hands up."
你听到你刚才说了什么吗
Do you hear what you just said?
我们生活在一个复杂的世界里 斯塔尔
We live in a complicated world, Starr.
不 不 对我来说没那么复杂
No. No, it doesn't seem that complicated to me.
我们要正义 警察无耻
我全程都会在这里
I'll be out here the whole time.
如果你想问我任何问题 那都是你的权利
And if you need to ask me anything, that's your right.
你的父母也会等着你
And your parents will be here waiting.
好的
Mm-hmm. Okay.
我超爱你的
I love you so much.
我也爱你
I love you.
请在陪审员面前说出你的名字
Now state your name for the grand jurors.
我叫斯塔尔·阿玛拉·卡特
My name is Starr Amara Carter,
今年16岁
and I'm 16 years old.
我将会询问你
I'm going to be asking you for a factual account
关于卡里尔·哈里斯被杀当晚你看到的事情
of what you saw the night Khalil Harris was killed.
我会把看到的都告诉你
I will tell you everything.
我会把我知道的都告诉你
I will tell you everything and more.
卡里尔的妈妈有毒瘾
Khalil lost his mother to crack.
卡里尔喜欢唱歌 虽然他唱得很烂
Khalil loved to sing even though he couldn't.
卡里尔在我家吃了五年的饭
Khalil ate at our house for five years.
卡里尔从来不哭
Khalil never cried.
卡里尔想去埃及
Khalil wanted to go to Egypt.
卡里尔和我接吻过两次
Khalil kissed me twice.
其中一次就在那晚
Once on that night.
卡里尔并没有枪
Khalil didn't own a gun.
卡里尔有一把梳子
Khalil owned a hairbrush.
卡里尔死的时候还握着那把梳子
Khalil died holding his hairbrush.
如果卡里尔还活着
And if Khalil was still alive...
他会从高中毕业
he would be graduating high school.
我猜 你一时半会不能让这事情过去了
So, I guess you're not gonna get over it anytime soon?
让事情过去
Get over it?
是啊 让它过去
Yes. Get over it.
你甚至都没发觉你自己是种族歧视 对吧
You can't even see that you're acting racist, huh?
因为 我不是
'Cause I'm not.
平时一副我们 大家
It's all "our," and "us,"
黑命贵的样子 你在电梯里遇到一个黑人
and "black lives matter, girl" until you clutch your purse
就得把钱包收起来
when you're in the elevator with a black person.
不一定非要用N开头的词
You don't need to use the N-word
或者是用水枪喷黑人
and use a firehose on black people
才叫歧视 海莉
to be racist, Hailey.
你变了 斯塔尔
You're different, Starr.
我变了
I'm different?
怎么 我是位没威胁的黑人女孩
What, I'm the nonthreatening black girl?
是啊 你是
Yeah. You are.
你朋友不是 他是个毒贩
Your friend wasn't. He was a drug dealer.
总有一天会有人杀了他
Someone was probably gonna kill him eventually.
你认真的吗 海莉
Are you serious, Hailey?
是的 警察看到了武器
Yes. The officer did see a weapon.
- 他看到一把梳子 - 看起来像是武器
- He saw a hairbrush. - That looked like a weapon.
你说我手里这是什么
What's this in my hand right now?
你跟我讲这东西像武器
You're gonna tell me that this looks like a weapon?
在他手里拿着 是的
In his hand, yes.
那在我手里呢
What about in my hand?
啊
Huh?
啊 像武器吗
Huh? Does it look like a weapon?
现在看起来像武器了吗
Does it look like a weapon now?
你给我趴在地上 快
Get on the ground! Now!
趴在地上 否则我就开枪了
Down on the ground before I shoot you!
不要动
Don't move!
不要动 否则我就开枪了
Don't move before I shoot you with it!
我刚刚说什么来着
What the hell did I just say?
别动 海莉
Don't move! Hailey.
看着我 不要哭了
Look at me and stop crying.
就是这种感觉
That's what it's like.
斯塔尔
Starr.
嘿 斯塔尔 慢着
Hey. Starr, wait.
- 斯塔尔 慢着 - 你想怎么样
- Starr, wait! - What do you want?
别这样
Hold on!
斯塔尔
Starr.
住手
Stop.
斯塔尔 斯塔尔 住手 你会伤到自己的
Starr. Starr, stop. You're gonna hurt yourself.
过来 过来
Come here. Come here.
有我呢
I got you.
快来 亲爱的
来接赛文 国王打了他
嘿 莱瑞克 赛文在哪
Hey, Lyric. Where's Seven?
斯塔尔 该死
- Starr! - Shit!
- 你来做什么 - 伤到哪里了
- What are you doing here? - Where is it hurting?
你们趁国王没回来快走
Y'all leave before King comes back.
他去找你了
He's looking for you.
没事 赛文 我们走
Nah, Seven. We're leaving.
来 帮我一下
Come on, help me out.
快来我们走
Come on. Let's go.
阿伊莎 怎么回事
Iesha, what happened?
怎么回事
What happened?
你告密 就要被打
You snitched and earned an ass whoopin'.
我儿子替你挨打而已
My baby took it for you.
血流了我家一地 快把他带走
Bleedin' all on my floor and shit. Get him outta here.
把肯雅和莱瑞克也带上
Take Kenya and Lyric with you, too.
莱瑞克 为啥
Lyric? What?
你们烦着我了
Y'all bothering me.
我就想一个人喝喝酒
Trying to get my drink on and shit.
走吧
Go!
见鬼
Shit!
见鬼 国王回来了
Shit. King back.
你们快走 从后门走
Y'all, come on. Go out the back door!
阿伊莎
- Iesha? - Huh?
谢谢你
Thank you.
嘿 亲爱的
Hey, baby.
我们必须带他去医院
We gotta get him to a hospital.
前面左转
Make a left up here.
要什么 为卡里尔伸张正义
- What? - Justice for Khalil!
出什么事了
What's goin' on?
要什么 为卡里尔伸张正义
- What? - Justice for Khalil!
请问
Excuse me.
出什么事了
What happened?
市政厅那边在示威了
There's a protest at City Hall.
...总有人遭到杀害
...people always getting murdered.
抱歉 斯塔尔
I'm sorry, Starr.
我们走吧
Let's go.
我现在就想走
I wanna go. Now.
为卡里尔伸张正义
Justice for Khalil!
Justice for Khalil! Justice for Khalil!
为卡里尔伸张正义
Justice for Khalil!
斯塔尔 斯塔尔
Starr. Starr!
为卡里尔伸张正义
适可而止 我不是靶子
我们要正义
嘿 是真的吗
Hey, is it true?
警察被放走了 不判刑 没惩罚
Cop goes free. No trial, nothing.
陪审团没有起诉
The grand jury didn't indict.
斯塔尔
Starr?
适可而止 我们要正义
卡里尔白死了
They killed Khalil for nothing!
- 烧了他们 - 为卡里尔伸张正义
- Burn it down! - We want justice for Khalil!
- 他们不停地杀害无辜的黑人 - 想抓我吗 那就来抓啊
- They keep killing us! - Gonna arrest me? Then do it!
不 莱瑞克不应该来这里
No, Lyric shouldn't be here.
是啊 走吧 莱瑞克 我们离开这里
Yeah, come on, Lyric. Let's get outta here.
赛文 你也得离开这里
Seven, you need to get outta here, too.
不 我要留在这里
No, I'm staying right here.
- 但是你受伤了 - 我没事
- But you're hurt. - I'm fine.
这才是民主的样子
This is what democracy looks like!
你需要我做什么
What do you need me to do?
我想帮忙
I wanna help.
带上莱瑞克和肯雅 离开这里
Take Lyric and Kenya, get them outta here.
确保他们安全 好吗
Make sure they're safe, okay?
斯塔尔 我不能把你留在这里
Starr, I'm not leaving you here.
我哪儿也不去
I'm not going anywhere.
我需要留下
I need to be here.
我没事
I'm good.
好吗
Okay?
好吧
Okay.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我们要正义
我们要什么
What do we want?
为卡里尔伸张正义
Justice for Khalil!
什么时候要 现在
- When do we want it? - Now!
我们要什么 为卡里尔伸张正义
- What do we want? - Justice for Khalil!
什么时候要 现在
- When do we want it? - Now!
我们要什么 为卡里尔伸张正义
- What do we want? - Justice for Khalil!
什么时候要 现在
- When do we want it? - Now!
我们要什么 为卡里尔伸张正义
- What do we want? - Justice for Khalil!
什么时候要 现在
- When do we want it? - Now!
我们要什么 为卡里尔伸张正义
- What do we want? - Justice for Khalil!
什么时候要 现在
- When do we want it? - Now!
我们要什么 为卡里尔伸张正义
- What do we want? - Justice for Khalil!
我们哪儿也不去
We ain't goin' nowhere!
我们要拿回属于黑人的权利
We're takin' it back.
- 黑人万岁 - 没错
- Black power! - That's right!
他们无缘无故杀了卡里尔
And they killed Khalil over nothin'!
太扯淡了
That's some bullshit!
是啊 烧了他们
Yeah, light him up, Bulldog!
为卡里尔伸张正义
Justice for Khalil!
我们不再忍受
我在此命令街上群众
I hereby command those on the street
警察
尽快散去
to immediately exit the roadway.
你们违反了150266号法令
You are in violation of code 150266.
你觉得我们是闹着玩的
You think it's a game?
你觉得我们在开玩笑
Think it's a joke?
你们有三分钟时间散去
You have three minutes to disperse,
否则你们将被逮捕与拘禁
or you will be detained or arrested.
列成阵线
One solid line!
大家冷静 慢慢停下
Come on, y'all! De-escalate!
Calm down, y'all! De-escalate!
他们只是在执行公务 好了 都站住
They're just doing their job. Come on, hold back!
别激动 别激动
Relax! Relax!
你站错边了 兄弟
You on the wrong side, brother.
你应该站在我们这边的 对吧
You're supposed to be one of us. Huh?
我们不会离开市政厅
We will not leave City Hal
因为我们有权为了自由而战
because we have the rigt to fight for our freedo.
没错
That's right!
为自由而战是我的责任
It is our duty to fight for our freedom!
我们必须取胜
It is our duty to wi!
It is our duty to win!
我们必须互相支持互相关爱
We must love and support one another!
失去社群的支持就是失去一切
We have nothing to lose but our chains!
举起手来 别开枪
- Hands up! - Don't shoot!
- Hands up! - Don't shoot.
举起手来 别开枪
- 举起手来 - 奥芙拉小姐
- Hands up! - Miss Ofrah?
别开枪
Don't shoot!
Don't shoot! Don't shoot!
你准备好利用你的武器了吗
You ready to use your weapon?
拿着就和枪一样重
It's as heavy as a gun.
别开枪
Don't shoot.
如果115号警员把枪换成这个
If 115 had traded his weapon for this one...
你可能是下一个
卡里尔·哈里斯安息
卡里尔就能活下来
Khalil would still be alive.
别开枪
Don't shoot.
我的
My...
别开枪
Don't shoot.
我叫斯塔尔
My name is Starr!
就是我目睹了卡里尔的死
And I'm the one who saw what happened to Khalil!
我是目击证人
I am the witness!
你们也一样
But so are y'all!
对
Yeah!
我们都是这不公正的目击证人
We are all witnesses to this injustice!
我们都看到了
We see it all!
我们要让全世界也都看到
And we will not stop until the world sees it too!
对
Yeah!
我们不会停止抗议
We will not stop protesting!
对
Yeah!
每个人都想问卡里尔是怎么死的
Everyone wants to talk abot how Khalil died.
而这无关于他的死
This ain't about how Khalil died.
- 这是关于他如何活着 - 对
- It's about how he lived. - Yeah.
卡里尔曾经活过
Khalil lived!
他的生命很重要
His life mattered!
我数到三你们就必须散去
You have till the count of three to disperse.
你在瞎扯什么呢 混蛋
What y'all talkin' about, man?
卡里尔活过
Khalil lived!
对
Yeah!
我们要正义
We need justice!
一
One!
卡里尔活过
Khalil lived!
对
Yeah!
二
Two!
卡里尔活过
Khalil lived!
对
Yeah!
三
Three!
卡里尔活过
- Khalil lived! - Yeah!
行动
Move!
退后
Go back!
不管我们说什么
No matter what we say...
不管我们喊得多大声
no matter how loud we shout...
住手
Stop!
放开
Let's go!
他们充耳不闻
...they refuse to hear us.
散开
Disperse!
你们需要立即散去
You need to disperse immediately.
如果你们还滞留在街上
If you are in the middle of the street,
你们就属于非法集会
you are unlawfully assembled
将遭到逮捕
and you will be subject to arrest.
快离开
Do it now!
你们违反了150266号法令
You are in violation of code 150266!
散开
Disperse!
如果你们不走
If you do not disperse...
就会被逮捕
you will be arrested.
我们命令你们立刻离开
You are commanded to immediately disperse.
我就说会是这样的结果
This is what I'm talkin' about!
此次集会
This gathering has been declared
属于非法集会
an unlawful assembly.
快走 快走 快走
Move! Move! Move!
快走 快走
Move! Move!
你别碰我
Can't touch me!
黑人商户
没错
That's right!
你被逮捕了
You're under arrest!
我喘不上气了
I can't breathe!
嘿 嘿 嘿 那不是麦弗的孩子么
Hey! Hey! Hey! Ain't y'all Mav's kids?
对
Yeah.
快上来
Get in the back!
慢 慢 慢 能带我们走吗
Wait! Wait! Wait! Hey, can we get in?
好 上车 我们走 上来
Yeah, come on. Let's go. Get in.
我的眼睛像是着火了
My eyes are on fire!
我们需要牛奶
We need milk.
去我爸爸店里
Go to my dad's store.
好 知道了
All right, gotcha.
你们需要立即散去
You need to disperse immediately!
你们将会被
You will be...
我们快进去
Let's get in here.
进来 快点 嘿 我们走 来吧
Get in. Come on. Hey, let's go. Come on.
黑人店铺
快帮我拿牛奶
Yo, come help me get this milk!
给 快点 快点
Here, hurry up! Hurry up!
倒在脸上 倒在他脸上
Pour it on his face. Pour it on his face!
快点 快点 快点
Come on! Come on! Come on!
谢了 小朋友
Thanks, little homie.
如果我看到你爸爸 我会告诉他你们在这里
If I see your pops again, I'll tell him where y'all at.
- 什么 你看到我爸爸了 - 是
- Wait, you saw our daddy? - Yeah.
是 他出来找你们了
Yeah, he was looking for y'all.
哟 我们走
Yo, let's roll.
赛文 你感觉怎么样
Seven, how you feeling?
不行 不行 还是疼
Nah, it still hurts.
好 我找人来帮你 好吗
Okay, we gonna get you some help, all right?
妈妈来电话了
Mama called.
她说什么
What'd she say?
斯塔尔
Starr, baby, call me
有空赶紧给我回电话 好吗
as soon as you get this, okay?
斯塔尔·阿玛拉 我知道
Starr Amara, I knw you are getting
你收到了信息 回电话
these message. Call me!
哦 你没时间给我打电话
Oh, so you can't retun my calls,
就有时间在电视上带头示威 还扔催泪瓦斯
but you can lead protests and throw tear gas on TV?
我发誓 你再不给我回电话
I swear, I am going to snath
我就打死你
the life out of you if you don't call m!
我们麻烦大了 斯塔尔
We're in some deep shit, Starr.
看来只能逃到墨西哥去了
About time we moved to Mexico.
你很清楚
You know damn well
对我们的妈妈来说 墨西哥不够远
Mexico ain't far enough for our mama.
该死
- Shit! - Whoa.
快 后门 我们走
Come on! Back door, let's go!
- 见鬼 锁住了 - 该死
- Shit! It's locked! - Shit!
我没有钥匙 门锁住了
I don't have a key! It's locked!
加油 加油 加油 加油 斯塔尔
Come on! Come on! Come on! Come on, Starr!
该死 该死 该死
Shit! Shit! Shit!
该死 该死
Shit! Shit!
卡特杂货店
我的天
Oh, my God.
刘易斯
Lewis!
商店着火了
The store's on fire!
太烫了
It's hot!
哇 哇 哇 快看
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa! Look!
我的天
Oh, Lord!
孩子们困在里面
The kids are stuck in there!
救命
Help!
不知道还有没有其他出口
I wonder if there's another way in.
后门 有个后门
Back there! It's around the back!
就在那边
Over here!
锁住了
It's locked!
孩子们被困在里面了
These kids stuck up in there!
救命 救命
Help! Help!
救命 这边 这边
- Help, over here! - Over here!
嘿 来了 小心 小心
Hey, come on, y'all. Watch out! Watch out!
有钥匙吗 有钥匙吗
Got a key? Got a key?
深呼吸
Breathe!
转过身 没事了 没事了 深呼吸
Turn around. It's okay. It's okay, breathe.
深呼吸 没事了
Breathe, come on. It's okay.
- 斯塔尔 赛文 - 好了 没事了
- Starr! Seven! - All right, come on.
我们走吧
Let's get out of here.
你没事吧 你没事吧
Are you okay? Are you okay?
我警告过你 麦弗
I warned you, Mav.
国王
King!
你这个混蛋
You son of a bitch!
你想怎么样 麦弗
What you gonna do, Big Mav?
我要弄死你这个混蛋
Imma kill your punk ass.
胡扯 你知道她是自找的
Shit, you knew she had it coming!
- 我们今晚做个了结 - 有种来啊 麦弗
- This ends tonight! - Come get some, Mav!
来啊
Come on!
别惹我爸爸
Leave my daddy alone!
瑟卡尼
Sekani!
瑟卡尼 把枪放下
Sekani, drop the gun.
瑟卡尼 快把枪放下
Sekani! Just put the gun down.
嘿 把枪放下
Hey! Drop the gun!
瑟卡尼 不 不 不 别开枪
Sekani, no! No! No! Don't shoot!
别紧张 我是警察
Stand down! I'm a cop!
THUG LIFE（暴徒生涯）
T-H-U-G L-I-F-E.
就是这样
This is it.
你给婴儿灌输的仇恨 会毁了所有人
The Hate U Give Little Infants F's Everybody.
看看瑟卡尼吧
Look at Sekani.
他就是那个婴儿
He's the little infant.
仇恨的果实
The result of hate.
他马上就会毁了所有人
And he's about to fuck everybody.
这不是别人灌输的仇恨
It's not the hate you give.
这是我们灌输的仇恨
It's the hate we give.
但是我们可以打破这个循环
But we can break the cycle.
不
No!
我们还要死多少人你们才会懂
How many of us have to die before y'all get it?
不要再这样了
No more.
我真的为你骄做
I'm real proud of you.
好了 没事了
Okay, it's okay.
我真的为你骄傲 恩
I'm real proud of you. Yeah.
都结束了 没事了
It's over. It's all right. Come on.
我们走 上车 我们回家
Let's go. Get in the car. Let's go home.
重建
"Rebuild."
暴动刚结束不到两个小时
The riots weren't more than two hours behind us
爸爸对我说了这句话
before Daddy said those words.
我知道我们会重建的
And I knew we would.
尤其是王侯帮的老大因为纵火被抓了起来
Especially with King going down for setting the fire.
每个人都出来作证
Everybody spoke up about what happened.
鲁本先生 刘易斯先生 甚至爸爸
Mr. Reuben, Mr. Lewis, even Daddy said something.
不许告密的规矩没了
Snitch rules no longer apply.
警察抓了老大 这都多亏了整个社区人民的帮助
Cops took down King, thanks to the whole community.
我家恢复了平静
The family's all good again.
就连爸爸和卡洛斯叔叔都不吵架了
Even Daddy and Uncle Carlos stopped beefin'.
妈妈和爸爸说我们暂时
Mama and Daddy said we're stayin'
还会住在花园高地
in Garden Heights for now.
这是我们的社区
This is our neighborhood.
我们的家
Our home.
- 亲爱的 - 怎么了
- Baby? - What?
间隔大一点 你放得太近了
Space it out a little bit more. You have 'em too close.
不 没事的 真的 这样可以
No, it's fine. Honestly, really, it's fine.
你一个人都干完了
You doin' all the work.
嘿 嘿 小子 你干什么
Hey! Hey, man, what you...
- 瑟卡尼 别闹了 - 快别喷水了 嘿
- Sekani, all right, stop! - Stop sprayin'!
别闹了
- Hey, come on! - Hey!
我来抓你了 小子
I'm gonna get you, boy!
瑟卡尼依然不负他的名字
Sekani's no doubt gonna live up to his name.
快乐 他依旧拥有这种力量
Joy. He's still got it...
不知怎么
somehow.
赛文·卡特
Seven Carter.
祝贺毕业
赛文依旧完美
Seven's still perfect.
好棒
Yeah!
不错 亲爱的 加油
That's right, baby! Go on!
明年秋天他就要去上大学了
Next fall, he's off to college.
妈妈说要原谅并且继续生活
Mama said forgive and move on.
但是我并不需要单方面的友谊
But I don't need a one-sided friendship.
因为我有真正的朋友
Not when I have real friends.
至于克里斯
And Chris?
我们终于看清了彼此
We finally see each other.
斯塔尔
Starr...
我在打扫卡里尔的房间
I'm cleanin' out Khalil's room.
你想要什么就来拿走吧
You go on in there and get what you like.
扫到毯子下面
Sweep it all beneath the rug
不代表灰尘不会散开
Doesn't make the dirt come up
有一把火在燃烧
There's a fire burning up
唯一比仇恨更强的
Only thing stronger than hate is love
是爱 我们需要改变
We need a change
奇异恩典
The song "Amazing Grace"
不会继续沉默
Won't be quiet anymore
直到他们听我们听得一清二楚
Not unless they hear us loud and clear
伤害无法逆转
Damage can't be undone
不要假装消失
Let's not pretend it disappears
我们需要改变
We need a change
奇异恩典
Or the song "Amazing Grace"
我们一步步来
Let's go step by step
一砖一瓦
And brick by brick
我负重前行
I'll carry the weight
都为了你
For you
卡里尔
Khalil.
我发觉这个名字也有特殊的意义
I found out that name means something, too.
朋友
Friend.
我永远不会忘记
I'll never forget.
我永远不会沉默
I'll never be quiet.
斯塔尔 卡里尔 娜塔莎
我无法改变我来自何处
I can't change where I come from
我的经历
or what I've been through...
所以为什么要为自己的出身感到羞愧
so why be ashamed of what makes me me?
我要坚持做自己
And I'm gonna keep on being Starr.
不再有第二个版本
No Version Two.
只有一个斯塔尔
Just Starr.
爸爸说我的名字赋予了我超能力
Daddy says my name gives me my own superpower.
我要好好使用这超能力
To use it.
这正是我要做的
And that's what I'm gonna do.
照亮黑暗
Light up the darkness.
该电影的拍摄及宣传
创造了超过13000个工作岗位及上千工时